云最重要的是协作。
The most important thing about the cloud is collaboration.
字幕：@小红马里奥
您可以向某人发送链接，然后你们就可以立即合作。
You can send someone a link and you're working together right away.
但云的缺点是您实际上没有该软件。
But the downside of the cloud is that you don't actually have the software.
因此，我们认为您应该拥有计算机上的程序和数据的副本
And so what we think you should have is a copy of the program and the data on
，但它仍然应该能够与其他人协作。
your computer, but it should still be able to collaborate with other people.
欢迎来到 localfirst.fm 播客。
Welcome to the localfirst.fm podcast.
我是主持人 Johanna Schickling，是一名 Web 开发人员、初创公司创始人，
I'm your host, Johanna Schickling, and I'm a web developer, a startup founder, and
热爱软件工程技术。
love the craft of software engineering.
在过去的几年里，我一直致力于使用网络技术构建现代、高品质的
For the past few years, I've been on a journey to build a modern, high quality
音乐应用程序。
music app using web technologies.
在这样做的过程中，我陷入了本地第一软件的困境。
And in doing so, I've been falling down the rabbit hole of local first software.
这个播客是邀请您加入我的旅程。
This podcast is your invitation to join me on that journey.
在本期节目中，我将采访 Peter van Hardenberg，他帮助
In this inaugural episode, I'm speaking to Peter van Hardenberg, who helped to
创造并推广了“本地优先”一词。
coin and popularize the term Local First.
作为 Ink & Switch研究实验室的主任，他在十年的大部分时间里一直处于
As the director of the Ink & Switch Research Lab, he's been on
这项工作的最前沿。
the forefront of this work for the better part of a decade.
我今天与他的对话首先介绍了本地
My conversation with him today starts with the basics of what Local
优先是什么以及为什么您（应用程序开发人员）应该关心它。
First is and why you, an application developer, should care about it.
在开始之前，还要非常感谢 Expo 和 Crab Nebula 对
Before getting into it, also a big thank you to Expo and Crab Nebula for
这个播客的支持以及对整个本地第一生态系统的支持。
supporting this podcast and supporting the local first ecosystem as a whole.
现在是我对彼得的采访。
And now my interview with Peter.
你好，欢迎彼得。 非常
Hello, welcome Peter.
感谢您今天能和我一起开始这个新的播客。
Thank you so much for making it today to kick off this new podcast with me.
那么你介意介绍一下自己吗？
So would you mind introducing yourself?
是的。 大家
Yeah.
好，我叫彼得·范·哈登伯格。
Hi, my name is Peter Van Hardenberg.
我是Ink & Switch 研究实验室的主任。
I am the director of Ink & Switch Research Labs.
我们是一个独立的工业研究实验室，研究
We're an independent industrial research lab studying the future
计算和思维工具的未来。
of computing and tools for thought.
惊人的。
Awesome.
彼得和我认识已经有一段时间了。
Peter and I have known us for quite a while.
当时，Peter 刚刚结束他在 Heroku 的最后一章，
Back then, Peter, has been just closing up his last chapter at Heroku
我一直是 Heroku 的忠实粉丝。
which I've been always a big fan of.
Peter 现在找到了致力于本地优先并定义本地优先的方法。
Peter found his way now working on local first and defining what local first is.
在深入探讨之前，是什么让您首先选择本地化？
Before going into it, what has led you to local first?
是的，我的意思是，显然这有点背离，对吧？
Yeah, I mean, obviously it's a bit of a departure, right?
就像，我在这里构建一个平台即服务。
Like, here I was building a platform as a service.
您知道，Heroku，对于那些不知道的人来说，基本上是一个主机，
You know, Heroku, for those who don't know, is a, basically a host
主要是在它开始用于 Rubyon Rails 应用程序时，但随着
Primarily when it started for Ruby on Rails applications, but over
时间的推移几乎可以用于所有内容。
time for pretty much everything.
Heroku 背后的想法是，你可以在你的机器上构建一个应用程序，
And the idea behind Heroku is that you could build an app on
然后推送它。
your machine and then push it.
对于持续交付系统，它将把它放在云中，并且
To a continuous delivery system, and it would put it live in the cloud, and there
今天还有其他类似的系统，您可以想象它，如您所知，原始 Netlify
are other systems like that today, you can imagine it as you know, proto Netlify
或早期的容器化云。
or early kind of, containerized cloud.
是的，从试图让每个人的
Yeah, and it is a bit of a departure to go from trying to get everybody's
应用程序在云中运行到告诉人们也许他们应该
apps running in the cloud to telling people that maybe they should
在自己的计算机上运行它们，这有点背离。
just run them on their computer.
所以我想我真的应该解释一下我们是如何到达那里的。
So I guess I should really explain how we got there.
我觉得对我来说。
I think for me.
我想讲一个关于在旧金山乘坐火车和地铁的故事。
I'd like to tell a story about riding the train in San Francisco, the subway there.
我的朋友们一直在开发一款名为 Rdio 的音乐应用程序，它是
And my friends had been working on a music app called Rdio which was
Spotify 的竞争对手。
sort of a competitor to Spotify.
他们已经不在身边了。
They're not around anymore.
你知道，当我乘坐这趟火车时，当火车在地面上时，我一直
And you know, as I was riding on this train, I had been listening
在在线模式下听音乐。
to music in the online mode when the train was above ground.
然后当我们进入隧道时，音乐就停止了。
And then when we went into the tunnel, the music would just stop working.
这真的让
And it was really...
我感到不安，因为我无法返回，甚至无法再听我已经
upsetting to me because like I couldn't go back and even listen to songs I'd already
听过的歌曲，或者无法滚动浏览我的播放列表，因为我没有处于
listened to or like scroll through the playlists that I had because I wasn't in
离线模式，而我只记得 有这种感觉，就像我们真的搞砸了，
offline mode and I just remember having this feeling like we've really blown it
我们已经把软件从这个东西变成了你可以拥有的东西，就像他们称之为
we've turned software from this thing that you can just have like they call it an
信息商品一样，这意味着就像你知道复制它
informational good that means that like you know the marginal cost of copying it
并使用它的边际成本为零一样，就是这样 这个想法是，类似的软件已经从
and using it as zero it's just it was this idea that like software had gone from this
任何人都可以拥有副本的东西变成了甚至在火车上都无法使用的东西，
thing that anyone could have a copy of To a thing that didn't even work on the train
因为我真的没有这个应用程序。
because I didn't really have the app.
尽管我手里的数据就在我面前的屏幕上，在
Even though I'd had the data in my hand on my screen in front of me, in
我的耳朵里听着，但不知怎的，在
my ears listening to it, somehow it had just completely evaporated in the time
火车进入隧道的时间里，它就完全消失了。
it took a train to go into a tunnel.
正确的。
right.
坐火车可不是那么回事。 就
And riding a train is not this out there thing.
好像这就是日常的事情一样。
It's like this is a daily thing.
是的，这是我每天的通勤。
Yeah, is my daily commute.
而且，你知道，有人说，哦，是的，你知道，
And, you know, there are people out there who say, Oh, yeah, you know, the
下周互联网将无处不在，你最近坐过地铁吗？
Internet's going to be everywhere next week, and have you taken a subway lately?
你知道，就像，都在大城市，对吧？
You know, and like, both in big cities, right?
你有这个问题，而且在更多的农村社区也有，对吗？
You have this problem, but also in more rural communities, right?
有很多地方没有互联网，或者互联网很慢。
There's lots of places where there's no Internet, or the Internet is slow.
你甚至可以在有互联网的地方，对吧？
And you can even be in places where there is Internet, right?
但冰箱旁边的手机接收信号不太好，
But your cell phone reception isn't great next to the fridge,
或者 Wi-Fi 信号中断。
or your Wi Fi has a cut out.
每天当我想离开家时都会遇到这种情况，
Faced this every day when I'm just like leaving the house and there's just this
wifi 就会停止响应。
little gap of the wifi stops responding.
有一点信号，我的应用程序就无法正常工作了。
There's a little bit of signal and my apps just don't work properly anymore.
是的，一切都被锁定了。
Yeah, everything kind of locks up.
你的手机只是一块小黑砖，没有良好的 Wi-Fi 连接。
Your phone is just a little black brick without a good Wi Fi connection.
这让我开始思考，为什么我们要按照
And so that got me thinking, like, well, why do we build
我们的方式来构建东西？
things the way we build them?
我认为，某种程度上的答案就是，你
And the answer to some extent, I think, was just that, you
知道，我们告诉人们这样做。
know, we told people to.
正确的。
Right.
我们让构建云应用程序变得容易，然后每个人都这样做了。
We made it easy to build apps for the cloud, and then everybody did.
是的。
Yeah.
是的，所以在 Heroku，我主要从事数据服务工作。
Yeah, and so at Heroku, I had worked on our data services mostly.
这就是我们的 Postgres 服务。
That was our Postgres service.
我开始思考问题的根源在于
And I started thinking about how really the problem is that the data
应用程序的数据实际上并不存在于您的设备上。
that you have for your application doesn't actually live on your device.
它存在于服务器上。
It lives on the server.
所以我开始思考，肯定有某种方法可以将这些数据
And so I started thinking, surely there's some way to get this data
从网络传输到计算机。
from the network down to the computer.
这很有趣。
And it's funny.
你知道，Johannes，你和我最初是通过 Prisma
You know, Johannes, you and I met originally through Prisma
和 GraphQL 以及数据库模式和诸如此类的东西认识的。 我
and GraphQL and database schemas and those kinds of things.
总是觉得这是一个非常相邻的问题，从
And this always struck me as a really adjacent problem, which is
根本上来说，在您的服务器上，您正在执行
that fundamentally, on your server, you're doing this process of taking
从数据库获取数据并将其输入您的 API 后端的过程。
data from a database and getting it into your sort of API back end.
然后，您执行一个单独的、不同的过程来将数据从
And then you do a separate, distinct process to get data from
API 获取到客户端，对吧？
the API to the client, right?
然后当它到达客户手中时，你就直接把它扔掉了。
And then when it gets to the client, you just kind of throw it away.
所以我开始思考，好吧，
And so I started thinking like, well, maybe it would make a lot more
如果我们只是在这些点之间同步数据而不是一直
sense if we just sort of synchronized data between those points instead of
按需获取数据，也许会更有意义。
fetching it on demand all the time.
事实上，这就是离线模式已经运作的方式。
And in fact, that's sort of how offline modes already worked.
所以我开始越来越多地思考这个问题，并与
And so I started thinking more and more about this and got involved with
一些伟大的研究人员合作，比如马丁·克莱普曼（Martin Kleppmann），他目前在
some great fellow researchers like Martin Kleppmann, who's currently at
慕尼黑工业大学，但当时在剑桥，刚刚写了一篇论文。
TU Munich, but was at Cambridge at the time and had just written a paper about.
所谓的 JSON CRDT，它就像一种同步
What are called JSON CRDTs, which is like a technology for synchronizing
两个文档之间的更改的技术，而您不必只
changes between two documents in a way where you didn't just
破坏其中一个。
have to clobber one or the other.
是的，一件事引发了另一件事，我们已经致力于解决
And yeah, that one thing led to another, and we've been working on
这个问题大约五年了。
the problem for about five years now.
我想你很多年前就已经告诉过我这件事了。
I think you've been telling me about it already many years ago.
最初我不太确定，嘿，这只是
And initially I wasn't quite sure it's like, Hey, is this about only
离线模式吗，但我逐渐意识到，哦，还有更多内容。
offline mode, but step by step I realize, Oh, there's much more to it.
从根本上讲，这可以解锁更高质量的软件，
And like, fundamentally this can unlock much higher quality software
并且不会让我作为应用程序开发人员变得更困难，而且
and also not make it harder for me as an application developer, but
实际上使事情变得简单得多。
actually make things a lot simpler.
我们可能还没有完全做到这一点。
We're maybe not fully there yet.
但这是我完全认同的愿景。
But that's a vision I totally buy into.
因此，这就是引导你首先思考什么是本地化的路径。
So this is the path that has led you to think what becomes local first.
这个词是你创造的吗？
Did you coin that term?
因此，“本地”一词第一次出现是在我们有一天的一次通话中。
So the term local first came around in a call we had one day.
我想……
I think...
人们在实验室里给予了我信任，但这绝对是那些
Folks have given me credit at the lab, but it was definitely one of those
开放式的对话之一，我们中的几个人长期以来一直试图找到
open ended conversations where several of us were kind of trying to find the
合适的术语。
right term for this for a long time.
我实际上打算将其称为无服务器技术，
I'd actually planned to refer to this as serverless technology,
但后来亚马逊推出了这种所谓的无服务器技术，
but then Amazon came out with this so called serverless technology,
实际上它只是所有服务器。
which in fact was just all servers.
所以我觉得这有点令人沮丧和有点不安，
So I found that sort of like frustrating and slightly upsetting
因为它给人一种误导的感觉。
because it felt misleading.
但我们真的很喜欢将其称为本地优先技术的想法，因为
But we really like the idea of calling it local first technology because
这个想法是为了强调它并不是要废除云。
the idea was to emphasize that it's not about doing away with the cloud.
你知道，它并不是真正的无服务器。
You know, it's not really serverless.
实际上，我们想说的是，我们只是想优先考虑用户
What we wanted to say was actually, we just want to prioritize the user's
在设备上的体验，并使其能够轻松提供高质量的体验。
experience on their device and make that easy to deliver on high quality.
是的，我非常喜欢这样。
Yeah, I like that a lot.
您一直在提到在地铁上收听 Rdio 的故事，但这是
You've been mentioning the story of Listening to Rdio on the subway and that's
行不通的，但从应用程序开发人员的角度来看，您会
not working, but from an application developer perspective what would you
说是什么让您首先考虑本地的挫败感。
say were the frustrations that has led you to think about local first.
是的，我的意思是，有几件事。
Yeah, I mean, it's a few things.
其一是，如果您仅以应用程序开发人员的身份来考虑软件开发，那就有点
One is if you just think about software development as an app developer, it's
复杂了，对吧？
sort of obscenely complicated, right?
你必须构建一个客户端应用程序，可能使用 Node 和 JavaScript
You've got To build a client app, probably using Node and JavaScript
、React、Vite 和 tailwind以及所有这些技术。
and React and Vite and tailwind and all these technologies.
然后你必须像 API 后端一样进行构建，它是它自己独立的
Then you have to build like the API backend, which is its own separate kind
节点应用程序或现有应用程序的一部分，具有所有自己的类型，例如 JWT，
of node app or part of your existing app with all of its own sort of like JWTs
以及数据库同步技术和 GraphQL，而且你知道，你 正在
and, you know, database sync technologies and GraphQL and, you know, you're
构建整个系统。
building out all that whole system.
然后在这后面，你实际上有你的数据层，就像。
And then behind that, you actually have your data layer, which is like.
Postgres 等你在最小情况下得到最好的情况。
Postgres and so you have like in kind of the best case in the minimum case.
您知道，对于现代 Web 开发人员来说，您拥有他们所说的三层堆栈
You know, for of modern web dev, you've got this three tier stack as
，但现实是，它不仅仅是这三层。
they call it, but the reality is, it's not just those three tiers.
您还需要像寻呼机这样的职责，以便在出现问题时通知您。
You also need like pager duty for letting you know when things are down.
也许你正在使用一堆奇怪的亚马逊服务。
And maybe you're using like a bunch of weird Amazon services.
您正在处理 DynamoDB 问题。
You got a DynamoDB thing going on.
然后，你知道，没有人再在 Heroku 上托管东西了。
Then, you know, No one's hosting things on Heroku anymore.
你必须把东西放在上面，你知道，你需要一个 Kubernetes 集群。
You got to put stuff up on, you know, you need a Kubernetes cluster somewhere.
而且，你知道，这只是一团糟。
And, you know, it's just, it's a mess.
这非常复杂。
it's insanely complicated.
因此，就像
So there's just like a lot of complexity feels gratuitous for like making an
为足球队或其他东西制作应用程序一样，很多复杂性感觉都是不必要的。
app for your soccer team or something.
即使从工具的角度来看也不是这样，但
And not even from a tooling perspective, but just the minimal
对于通常非常简单的应用程序来说，最小的架构占用空间就已经足够了。
architectural footprint is quite a lot for often very simple apps.
这是正确的。 最
That's right.
重要的是，你必须支付所有费用。
And then on top of that, you have to pay for it all.
正确的。
Right.
你知道，也许你是一家 YC 初创公司，你会获得一些积分来
You know, maybe you're a YC startup, you get some credits to get you
开始，但这绝对是毒贩模式，对吧？
started, but that's definitely the drug dealer model, right?
就像第一个是免费的，对吧？
Like first one's free, right?
然后，你知道，我个人认识一些倒闭的公司，
And then, you know, I have personally known a number of companies that died,
尽管他们，呃，他们的产品正在迅速增长，但
even though they were, uh, their product was growing rapidly, but just the cost
运行基础设施的成本太高，无法证明该系统的合理性，对吗？
of running their infrastructure was too high to justify the system, right?
就像他们不知道如何能够将这家公司变成一家像风
Like they didn't see how they'd be able to turn this thing into a Like a venture
投支持的估值数十亿美元的公司一样。
backed billion dollar valuation company.
因此，尽管他们的产品很受欢迎且不断增长，但他们却无法获得任何资金来维持运营
And so they couldn't get any money to keep the lights on despite having
。
a popular and growing product.
所以这太疯狂了。
So that's crazy.
然后喜欢。
And then like.
即使最重要的是，比如说，假设您已经设法
Even on top of all of that, like, let's say that you've managed to, you know,
筹集到足够的资金来聘请整个团队随时为您服务，并且您成功地
raise enough money to hire an entire team to be on call for you and you managed
构建了一款您可以使用的产品 说服某人将成为十亿
to, you know, build a product that you can convince somebody will be a billion
美元，你知道，在某个时候评估业务，你学习所有这些
dollar, you know, valuation business at some point and you learn all of those
技能，你构建所有这些系统和一切，你知道，最终
skills and you build all those systems out and everything, you know, ultimately,
它仍然非常脆弱，对吧？
it's still very fragile, right?
在时间和空间中，你知道，我们现在都拥有所有
In In time, as well as in space, you know, we've all had all of these
我们喜欢和使用的产品，无论是谷歌阅读器
products now that we loved and used, whether it's, you know, Google reader
还是黑暗的天空，或者你知道，选择你最喜欢的最喜欢的死者 技术，你知道，
or dark sky or, you know, pick your favorite favorite dead tech, you know,
这些产品由创始人承担，当他们被收购时，他们发表了
and these products go on the founders, when they get acquired, they put up
这篇博客文章，讲述了构建这个产品的一段令人难以置信的旅程。
this blog post about what an incredible journey building this product has been.
而且，您知道，正在发生的令人难以置信的旅程是
And, you know, the incredible journey that's happening is that
您的软件和数据正在消失，您再也无法拥有它了。
your software with your data is going away and you can't have it anymore.
正确的。
Right.
他们正在被收购。
They're being acquired.
他们正在关闭一切。
They're shutting everything down.
如果你幸运的话，你知道，就像使用 Rdio 一样，你可以
And if you're lucky, you know, as with Rdio you can
下载一堆 JSON 文件。 作为用户，
download a bunch of JSON files.
这就是您剩下的一切了。
That's all that's left for you as the user.
我只想说，这是我们给自己制造的问题，对吧？
And I just want to say, like, this is a problem we created for ourselves, right?
就像，我可以去下载一个旧的Microsoft，你知道，MS DOS 副本，
Like, I can go and download an old Microsoft, you know, MS DOS copy of,
例如 WordPerfect 或80 年代末的其他东西，它仍然可以运行。
like, WordPerfect or something from the late 80s, and it'll still run.
你知道，我可以在软盘上得到厄运，它仍然会运行，但就像
You know, I can get doom on a floppy disk and it'll still run, but like
为云而出现的软件一样，你知道，它消失后就消失了。
software that came out for the cloud, you know, it's just gone when it's gone.
就是这样，对吧？
And that's it, right?
他们称这一段历史为“黑暗时代”，不是
This is, they call a certain period of history, the dark ages, not, you
因为它们很糟糕，而是因为它们对今天的我们来说是黑暗的，
know, formally because they were bad, but because they're dark to us today,
因为我们无法回去查看它们的记录 ，他们迷路了。
because We can't go back and look at the records from them, they were lost.
同样，我们已经建立了一个技术的黑暗时代。
And so similarly, we have built a dark age for technology.
不是说不好，有很多很棒的东西，但是
Not that it's bad, there are a lot of things that are great, but that there
这里不会有我们工作的记录，对吧？
won't be a record of our work here, right?
就像你和我正在构建的东西，
Like the things that you and I are building, the work that
我在 Heroku 所做的工作，我们在那里制作和发布的应用程序。
I did at Heroku, the apps that we've made and put out there.
因为它们不是，它们不存在于它们运行的​​一组服务器之外
Because they're not, they don't exist outside of the one set of servers they
，你知道，当它们离线时，它们就永远消失了。
run on, you know, when they go offline, that, that's it they're gone forever.
我认为这很糟糕。
And I think that kind of sucks.
是的，我完全同意。
Yeah, I fully agree.
我的意思是，在一步步进入软件开发之后，我
I mean, having gotten into software development, step by step, I
可以迈出第一步，用 HTML、CSS 构建一个小东西，
could take my first steps with building a little thing with HTML,
然后一步一步地，你想让它更实用、更真实。
CSS and step by step, you want to make it more functional, more real.
然后你开始拉动这条线，就像所有的复杂性都
And then you start pulling on that thread, like all that complexity comes
向你袭来，而且永无止境。
towards you and it's never ending.
因此，需要学习的东西太多，需要维护的东西太多，需要支付和操作的东西太多。
So it's so much to learn, so much to maintain, so much to pay for and operate.
所以我希望有一种更简单的方法来构建和运行事物。
So I wish there was a simpler way to, to build things and to run things.
所以也许这是一个很好的问题，什么是本地第一？
So maybe this is a good point to ask, what is local first?
什么是本地优先？
What is Local First?
本地优先软件是在您的计算机上运行并
local-first software is software that runs on your computer and
与其他人协作的软件。
collaborates with other people.
我们认为云最重要的是协作。
We think that the most important thing about the cloud is collaboration.
这种无处不在、随时可访问的数据副本可以从任何地方获取。
This ubiquitous, always accessible, copy of your data from anywhere.
您可以向某人发送链接，然后你们就可以立即合作。
You can send someone a link and you're working together right away.
无需下载，无需安装。
Nothing to download, nothing to install.
但云的缺点是您实际上没有该软件。
But the downside of the cloud is that you don't actually have the software.
因此，我们认为您应该拥有计算机上的程序和数据的副本
And so what we think you should have is a copy of the program and the data on your
，但它仍然应该能够与其他人协作，对吗？
computer, but it should still be able to collaborate with other people, right?
我们希望将云的优点与
We want the good parts of the cloud combined with the good
旧构建方式的优点结合起来。
parts of the old way of building.
在某种程度上，现在我们有很棒的协作工具，如
And in a way right now we have great collaboration tools like
Google Drive 和 Figma 等。
Google Drive and Figma, etc.
但默认情况下，这些工具都存储在云端。
But it's all by default lives in the cloud.
所以你建议让我们鱼与熊掌兼得，这样软件就可以
So you suggesting let's have the cake and eat it too, so that the software
在客户端上完全运行，我们只使用服务器来完成绝对必要的
fully works on the client and we only use the server for the absolutely necessary
部分，但仍然可以进行协作。
pieces but still have collaboration.
这是正确的。
That's right.
道格·恩格尔巴特（Doug Engelbart），你知道，一位著名的计算机科学研究
And Doug Engelbart, you know, a famous computer science
人员，他谈到了我们如何增强我们的智力。
researcher he talked about how we can de- augment our intellect.
我们可能会让事情变得更糟。
We can make things worse for ourselves.
他通过将一块砖头粘在铅笔上
And he demonstrated this really poetically by taping a brick to a pencil
并要求人们用它写字来真正诗意地展示了这一点。
and asking people to write with it.
所以我并不是说解决这些技术问题一定有免费午餐
So I'm not here to say that there are free lunches necessarily in solving these
，但我确实认为我们可能已经在铅笔上贴了一些巨大的砖块
technical problems, but I do think that we may have taped a few giant bricks
，并且我们已经解决了很多不必要的困难。
to our pencils here, and that there's a lot of unnecessary difficulty that
通过选择不太适合该任务的架构来引入。
we've introduced by picking architectures that are not well suited to the task.
在很多情况下，这些都是伟大的技术。
These are in many cases, great technologies.
只是我们正在部署与
It's just that we're deploying the same technology that we would use to
构建 10 亿人应用程序相同的技术来构建10 人应用程序或 100 万人应用程序。
build a billion person app to build a 10 person app or a million person app.
而且要求完全不同。
And the requirements are just radically different.
现在，我认为这种技术堆栈的同质化是
Now, I think this sort of homogenization of the technical stack is part of why
我们所处位置的部分原因。
we're in the position that we're in.
就像乔纳森·爱德华兹（Jonathan Edwards）所说的那样，你知道，我们被
Like Jonathan Edwards famously said, you know, we were
承诺为心灵提供自行车。
promised bicycles for the mind.
但他们却给了我们航空母舰，对吗？
But they gave us aircraft carriers instead, right?
所以，当我们需要自行车时，我们正在建造航空母舰。
So, so we're building aircraft carriers when we need bicycles.
这并不意味着航空母舰没有用处。
That doesn't mean that the aircraft carrier isn't useful.
如果你需要像美国海军一样在南太平洋投射兵力，它非常有用，
It's very useful if you need to project force in the South Pacific as the U.
-
S.
但如果你想去买杂货，它就没有多大帮助了。
Navy, but it's not terribly helpful if you want to go get groceries.
正确的？
Right?
这是不适合这项工作的工具。
It's the wrong tool for the job.
我们只是尝试用一套工具完成所有事情。
And we're just trying to do everything with one set of tools.
因此，您提到它基本上应该在没有服务器的情况下在我们的设备上完全运行，
So you've mentioned that it basically should work fully on our device
并且服务器通过提供
without the server and the server augments that software by giving
附加功能（例如协作）来增强该软件，也许它还有助于
it additional capabilities, such as collaboration, maybe it also helps
自动备份等。
with automatic backup, et cetera.
以便。
So, that.
非常清楚。
is very clear.
然而，目前还不是很清楚我将如何从通常
However, it would not be super clear yet how I would go from typically
构建一个三层 Web 应用程序转向在该模型中构建事物。
building a three tier web app to building things in that model.
我的直觉可能是添加大量缓存，等等。
My intuition would be maybe adding tons of caching, et cetera.
我还会拥有该服务器数据库吗？
Would I still have that server database?
那么我构建本地优先应用程序的典型方法是什么？
So what is the typical way how I built local first apps?
是的，你有两个主要问题。
Yeah, you kind of have two main problems.
有程序和数据，对吗？
There's the program and the data, right?
我们将其简单化。
We'll just kind of boil it down.
程序在某种意义上是容易解决的问题。
The program in some sense is the easy problem to solve.
所以，你知道，如果你在网络上，你想要的是一个 PWA，渐进式网络应用程序。
So, you know, if you're on the web, what you want is a PWA, progressive web app.
您将使用服务工作线程来缓存代码。
You're going to use a service worker to cache the code.
您将尝试在浏览器中运行所有内容，并且将
You're going to try and run everything in the browser, and you're going to
其存储起来，以便它可以离线工作。
keep it stored so it works offline.
如果您使用移动设备，在很多情况下您已经以这种方式进行构建，
If you're on mobile, in many cases you already build this way,
是的。
Yeah.
就像苹果公司或多或少发布的第一方发布的所有内容一样。
Like, everything that Apple publishes first party, more or less.
已经是本地优先了吧？
Is already local first, right?
就像苹果笔记一样。
Like Apple notes.
你不会在电梯里拿出手机来
It's not like you ever pull out your phone in the elevator to, like, make a
记下刚刚的谈话。
note from a conversation you just had.
你所看到的只是一个小旋转器。
And all you see is a little spinner.
不，这太荒谬了，对吧？
No, that's ridiculous, right?
就像苹果笔记那样，
Like Apple Notes,
我认为苹果笔记是应用程序应该是什么样的一个很好的例子，而
I think Apple notes is a great example of what an app should feel like, whereas
我很多时候在走廊上看到那个旋转器，而我
I do a lot of times see that spinner on the hallway where I don't have perfect
在其他应用程序中没有完美的互联网连接。
internet connectivity in other apps.
正确的？
right?
因为您在某人的办公室，并且想要记录一些
Because you're at somebody's office and you know, want to make some notes about a
不在 WiFi 或其他设备上进行的对话记录。
conversation not on the WiFi or something.
你会想，天哪，我需要
And you're like, Oh, God, I gotta
wifi 密码吗？
wiFi password?
是的，不，这太荒谬了。
Yeah, no, that's ridiculous.
我只是想在这里做个笔记。
I'm just trying to take a note here.
好的，那么，您需要在设备上获取该程序。
Okay, so, so you need to get the program on the device.
这是一个。
That's one.
然后你需要获取设备上的数据。
And then you need to get the data on the device.
那也是。
That's too.
那么如何获取设备上的数据呢？
So how do you get the data on the device?
好吧，在某些非常有限的情况下，您只需将数据放入程序中，对吗？
Well, in some very limited cases, you just put the data into the program, right?
所以，我不知道，也许这是棋盘
So like, I don't know, maybe it's a reference for a board
游戏或类似游戏的参考。
game or something like that.
您只需下载数据并将其留在应用程序中即可。
You can just download the data and leave it in the app.
但当然，这并不像这个有趣的案例。
But of course, that's not like the interesting case.
我想，很多应用程序，大多数应用程序，都有用户生成的内容。
A lot of apps, most apps, I think, you know, you have user generated content.
这就是你在那儿的原因，对吧？
That's why you're there, right?
它是一张地图，它是一个笔记，它是您在那里要做的任何事情。
It's a map, it's a note, it's whatever you're there to do.
在这种情况下，您需要什么。
And so in that case, what you need.
是一种将数据从云端获取到设备然后返回云端的方法。
Is some way to get data from the cloud to the device and then back to the cloud.
棘手的部分是你需要处理人们可以离线的事实。
And the tricky part is you need to deal with the fact that people can go offline.
所以这些数据基本上是我之前创建的一些数据。
And so that data is basically some data I might've previously created.
例如，如果它是 Apple笔记应用程序，那么可能是
For example, if it's the Apple notes app, then maybe some notes
我在 Macbook 上创建的一些笔记。
I've created on my Macbook.
我认为我们不需要过多讨论诸如如何交付该计划之类的问题。
I think we don't need to talk too much about like how do you deliver the program.
但数据方面似乎确实很棘手。
But the data aspect that seems really tricky.
那么您看到了哪些问题？
So what are the problems that you've seen?
当前的最佳实践或我们构建事物的不同方式是什么？
And what are the current best practices or different way how we can architect things?
是的。
Yeah.
再说一遍，我喜欢将其锚定在，我们是如何到达这里的？
And again, I like anchoring this in , how did we get here?
我们已经下载数据很长时间了。
We've been downloading data for a long time.
您可以从 Internet 获取 CSV 文件。
You can get a CSV file off the Internet.
您可以用Excel 文件向某人发送电子邮件，对吧？
You can email somebody in Excel file, right?
我们有点明白了，就像，然后你就得到了。
We kind of get that, like, then you have it.
你知道，我可以通过电子邮件给你发送一个Excel 文件，然后你就可以
You know, I can email you an Excel file and then you can
打开它，没什么大不了的，对吧？
open it like no big deal, right?
这看起来很容易。
That seems easy.
同样，就像我关于音乐应用程序的故事一样，
Similarly, like with my with my story about the music app, you know,
我可以下载这些播放列表并在设备上兑现它们。
I could download those playlists and just cash them on the device.
这就像你所说的一种谦虚的事情
And so that's like a kind of a modest thing you were
，只是缓存所有内容。
saying, just cache everything.
凉爽的。
Cool.
好的。
Okay.
只要你所做的就是读书，没什么大不了的。
As long as all you're doing is reading, no big deal.
没关系。
That's fine.
正确的？
Right?
那行得通。
That just works.
凉爽的。
Cool.
我们将缓存所有内容。
We'll cache everything.
问题是我们仍然希望能够在离线时工作。
The problem is that we also still want to be able to work when we're offline.
正确的？
Right?
我们的租户之一是，您永远不应该被阻止做您想做的事情。
one our tenants is you should never, ever be stopped from doing what you want to do.
由于另一台计算机的可用性或缺乏可用性。
By the availability or lack of availability of another computer.
我想说，这也许也是你可以划清界限的地方。
And I would say this is maybe also where you can draw a line between.
目前，还不是本地优先的软件，
Current, not yet local-first software that's not entirely useless in an
如果它缓存了很多东西，那么至少在离线场景下我还可以阅读它。
offline scenario if it caches things a lot, so at least I can read it.
但从那时起，它仍然允许您
But to go from there to that, it allows you to still do
完全离线完成工作。
the job completely offline.
我认为这有点像一个很难克服的障碍，
I think this is sort of like a barrier that is incredibly hard to overcome with
就像你对缓存的典型三层应用程序
like your more like typical three tier app
乐观一样
optimistic,
。
of caching.
是的，正是如此。
yeah, exactly.
不仅如此，而且，思考起来很复杂，对吧？
And it's not only that, but, like, it's just complicated to think about, right?
比如，有很多微妙的问题。
Like, there's a lot of subtle problems.
哦，如果您知道，请单击“确定”，然后它立即变为绿色
Oh, if you know, you click the OK and then it goes green right
，但实际上您正在后端运行 fetch，并且
away, but really you're running the fetch in the back end and
-
have an
发布请求失败。
post request failed.
现在我们已经告诉用户它有效了。
now we've already told the user that it works.
好的，现在我们需要提出例外。
Okay, now we need to like raise an exception.
让我们先确保检查我们是否在线。
Let's make sure that we check if we're online first.
哦，但是浏览器认为我们在线。
Oh, but the browser thought we were online.
但现在它只是，这是一场噩梦，因为
But now it's just, it's a nightmare as let's not do
我已经看过很多次了，基本上就像你所说的那样，哦，这太棒了。
I've seen many times that basically like shows you indicates, Oh, this was great.
然后你会看到一个小旋转器，弹出窗口，出现了问题。
And then you see like a little spinner, a pop up, something has gone wrong.
请重新加载
Please reload the
刷新浏览器。
Refresh the browser.
你已经失去了所有的工作。
You've lost all your work.
我一直以来最不喜欢的消息之一是 Google 文档。
One of my all time least favorite messages is on Google Docs.
有时，如果您处理文档，例如在飞机上，
Sometimes if you work on a document, like while you're on a flight,
即使您已经下载了该文档，也请记住添加扩展名，并在
even though you've downloaded it, remember to add the extension, cached
登机前将其缓存，以便可以离线使用。
it before you got on the plane so that it would be available offline.
然后您在航班上编辑文档，然后着陆并上
And then you edit the document on the flight and then you land and
线，它会说，我们很抱歉，当您离线时，此文档已更改
you come online and it says, we're sorry, this document has changed
太多。
too much while you were offline.
我们现在正在将您重置为云状态，然后您的所有数据都会消失。
We're now resetting you to the cloud state and then all your data is gone.
这种事只发生在我身上一两次，但是伙计，这很痛苦。
That's only happened to me once or twice, but man, that hurt.
我们所做的是，我们可以，你知道，如果只是你再次工作，
What we do is we can, you know, if it's just you working again, there's
这里真的没有任何问题，对吧？
not really any problem here, right?
就像我可以编辑数据一样。 然后
Like I can edit the data.
当我上线时，我们就上传它。
And then just when I come online, we upload it.
真正的挑战是，如果您有两个不同的东西，编辑
The real challenge is if you have two different things, editing
数据，然后需要合并它们的更改，对吧？
the data, and then you need to merge their changes, right?
就像我在播放列表中添加了一首曲目一样。
So like I added a track to the playlist.
而且，您知道，Spotify在播放列表中添加了一首曲目。
And, you know, Spotify added a track to the playlist.
好吧，现在我们有冲突了。
Okay now we have a conflict.
冲突是我们将在这里使用的技术术语。 这
Conflict is the technical term we're going to use here.
就是困难的事情。 多年来，
And so that's the hard thing.
许多不同的系统以不同的方式解决了这个问题
And lots of different systems have approached this in different
，对吗？
ways over the years, right?
就像，Git 使您能够合并冲突，只要您
Like, Git gives you the ability to merge conflicts as long as you
没有对同一文件或文件中的同一行进行编辑，对吧？
don't have edits to the same file or the same line in the file, right?
CouchDB 和 PouchDB，你知道，他们使用所谓的最后写入者获胜。
CouchDB and PouchDB, you know, they use what's called last writer wins.
所以无论哪个。
And so it's whichever.
你知道，所有系统都同意，无论最后一个是哪一个，
The, you know, all the systems agree that whichever the last one was will
现在都将覆盖最后一个。
overwrite now, which one was last.
好吧，现在我们开始讨论有趣的分布式
Okay, now we start to get into, like, interesting distributed
系统问题，因为你不能相信计算机上的时钟。
systems questions because you can't trust the clocks on the computers.
那么，这是服务器的最后一个1吗？
So, is it the last 1 to the server?
是否必须有一个中央服务器来决定？ 约翰内斯，
Does there have to be a central server that decides?
我们可以摆脱那个中央服务器吗？
Can we get rid of that central server, Johannes?
我们可以吗？
Can we?
剧透！
spoiler!
我们可以！
Yes, we can!
有点。
Sort of.
我们稍后再讨论这个问题。
We'll come back to that later.
这就说得通了。
That makes sense.
如果软件在我们的设备上运行并且数据也在我们的设备中，那么
If the software runs on our devices and if the data is also in our devices,
现在服务器在某种程度上被降级，不再需要
now the server is kind of demoted in a way no longer necessarily has to
扮演绝对的核心角色。
play that absolutely central role.
如果出现问题，客户端可以忘记所有内容并
If something goes wrong, the client can just forget everything and get
从服务器重新获取所有内容。
everything again from the server.
但这正是我们想要超越的一步，让
But that's exactly the step where we want to go beyond to have the work that
我们所做的工作让客户真正信任我们，然后与其他人合作。
we do and the clients to actually trust that and then collaborate with others.
这是正确的。
that's right.
我认为这个模型的美妙之处，我们之前谈到过想要
And I think the beauty of this model, and we talked earlier about wanting
让软件更简单，对吗？ 我们今天所拥有的
to make software simpler, right?
模型的很多复杂性都来自于拥有所有
A lot of the complexity of the model that we have today comes from having all
这些不同的系统和编程语言，就像
these different systems and programming languages and Like different computers
涉及每项任务的不同计算机一样，对吗？
involved in literally every task, right?
就像我在标准网络应用程序中勾选一个框一样，我已经有了我的计算机，
Like if I tick a box in a standard web app, I've got my computer, which
然后它向 API 服务器发送请求，然后 API 服务器对数据库进行访问
then sends a request to the API server, which then does a right to
，然后数据库需要将其传播回我的计算机。
the database, which then needs to propagate that back to my computer.
就像理论上的最佳情况一样。
So like, like best case theoretical.
我们涉及三个系统。
We've got three systems involved.
但实际上，还有API 网关之类的，你知道，请求
Practically, though, there's also like API gateways and like, you know, request
路由器之类的，就像一路上发生的所有其他东西一样，PG 代理
routers and like all this other stuff is happening along the way, PG proxy
保镖连接保镖以及所有这些，就像在名义上的三台服务器之上额外隐藏的复杂性
bouncer connection bouncers and all this like extra hidden complexity on top
。
of the sort of notional three servers.
然而，如果你可以移动它，以便你知道，是的，你勾选
Whereas if you can move that so that you know, yeah, you tick
该框，它就会在本地写入。
the box and it writes it locally.
就是这样。
That's it.
你现在就完成了。
You're done right now.
问题是，我如何让其他人知道我拿走了盒子？
The problem is, well, how do I let other people know that I took the box?
所以我们要做的就是建立起来。
And so what we're trying to do is set up.
我们称之为同步，对吧？
We call this synchronization, right?
因此，我们希望将您本地设备中的状态同步
So we want to synchronize the state that you have in your local device
到其他计算机，无论是云中的服务器还是与
to other computers, whether that servers in the cloud or other people
您协作的其他人。
who you're collaborating with.
所以我们正在做的是改变这种关系，而
And so what we're doing is we're kind of changing the relationship where instead
不是服务器来调解正在发生的事情。
of the server mediating what's happening.
正确的。
Right.
客户端决定它在做什么，然后它让服务器知道，
The client decides what it's doing, and then it lets the server know,
比如，嘿，我做了这个改变。
like, Hey, I made this change.
而且，你知道，我们可以逐步做到这一点。
And, you know, we can do that incrementally.
事实上，我们能做的就是记录本地计算机上发生的所有编辑，
And in fact, what we can do is record all the edits that are happening on your
然后将其日志发送到服务器。
local machine and then just basically send a log of that to the server.
然后类似地，服务器可以向您发送
And then similarly, the server can send you a log of any other
其他人所做的任何其他编辑的日志。 从
edits that other people have made.
某种意义上说，现在你遇到了一个更简单的问题，就像
And now you have, in some sense, a much simpler problem, which is
，好吧，好吧，我已经有了所有这些不同类型的改变。
just like, okay, well, I've got all these different sort of changes.
基本上我们有一个变更日志。
We have a change log, basically.
我们所要做的就是弄清楚如何将它们组合在一起以使其发挥作用。
And all we have to do is figure out how to put that together so that it works.
所以我认为那里有很多东西需要解开。
So I think there's a lot to unpack there.
所以我想了解你如何才能真正做到这一点？
So I'd like to understand how can you actually do that?
但在讨论之前，我还想知道这是否适用于
But before going into that I'm also wondering whether this works well for
某些类型的应用程序，但可能不适用于其他一些应用程序。
some kind of applications, but not maybe for some other applications.
所以我可以很好地想象这对于苹果笔记来说是如何工作的。
So I can very well imagine how this works for like Apple notes.
我可以想象这是如何工作的。
I could imagine how this works for like a.
更复杂的笔记系统，也许一直到Notion 的规模。
More complex note taking system, maybe all the way to the scale of Notion.
但我想知道的是，是否存在某个截止点，
What I'm wondering though, whether there's like some cutoff point where
这不再是一个好的方法。
this is no longer a good approach.
那么，如果我想象建立像 Facebook 这样的东西，这仍然是一个不错的选择吗？
So if I imagine building something like Facebook is that still a good fit?
对于本地优先的软件。
For local-first software.
是不是有点像沙子里的一条线，你说，也许理论上仍然
Is there kind of like a line in the sand where you say, maybe theoretically still
可行，但绝对不是一个好主意。
possible, but absolutely not a good idea.
什么适合本地优先软件，什么不适合？
What is good fit for local-first software and what isn't?
是的。
Yeah.
因此，本地优先软件的优势在于用户应该
So the strength of local-first software is when users should have
控制自己的数据，对吧？
control over their data, right?
当边缘设备需要能够独立运行时，
And when the devices at the edge need to be able to operate independently,
本地优先非常适合。
local first offers a great fit.
可能不太适合ATM，ATM 只是决定何时
Probably not a great fit for an ATM, aTM just deciding when
离线才能吐钱。
it's offline to spit out money.
你知道，没有任何办法让其他节点知道它在做什么。
You know, without any way to let other nodes know what it's doing.
当用户对数据拥有大量代理权和作者权时，本地优先
When the users have a lot of agency and authorship over the data, local-first
软件就非常有意义。
software makes a ton of sense.
如果您试图管理外部资源，例如银行帐户中的现金
If you're trying to manage an external resource, like cash in a bank account
或会议室预订或类似的东西，那么它就没有意义。
or a meeting room booking or something like that, then it makes less sense.
我认为社交媒体是一个有趣的中间立场。
I think social media is an interesting middle ground.
我认为有很多好处。
I think there's a lot of benefits.
赋予用户对其数据的控制权以及对其数据的代理权。
to giving users control over their data and an agency over their data.
但存在有趣的规模和索引问题。
But there's interesting scale and indexing problems.
所以我可以想象，事实上，有些社交网络
So I can imagine, in fact, there are social networks
首先是完全本地化的。
that are totally local first.
一个很好的例子就是“scuttlebutt”，
A great example of one is called scuttlebutt
它是本地第一个社交网络。
and that's a local first social network.
但你知道，它伴随着一系列架构权衡。
But you know, it comes with a bunch of architecture trade offs.
它专为离线使用而设计。
It's designed for offline use.
所以这意味着当你加入 Scuttlebutt 时，或者至少
And so that means when you join scuttlebutt, or at least
当我加入 Scuttlebutt 时，你必须下载大约 10 场演出《
When I joined Scuttlebutt, you had to download like 10 gigs
哇
Wow
帆船》之类的，你知道，社交媒体帖子，你永远不会
sailboats and like, you know, social media posts that you will never
阅读这些帖子，只是为了能够被引导进入 系统。
read just to be able to get sort of bootstrapped into the system.
不认为这是软件本地化的必然结果。
don't think that's a necessary consequence of local for software.
他们选择优先考虑的设计，就像你应该
design that they chose to prioritize, which is like you should be able
能够拥有整个辣酱玉米饼馅一样。
to have the whole enchilada.
但是，是的，我再次想，是的，我想另一个需要考虑的有用的事情
But yeah, I think again, right, like, I guess another useful thing
是用户多久会使用相同的数据？
to consider is like how often will users engage with the same data?
因此，就像维基百科一样，从某种意义上说，它可能不是一个出色的本地第一应用程序。
So, like, Wikipedia, probably not a great local first app in some sense.
尽管我听说帕特里克·科里森（Patrick Collison）建立了一个离线维基百科
Though I'm told Patrick Collison built an offline Wikipedia
作为他的第一个冒险项目之一。
as one of his first ventures.
所以，你知道，我想它是有用的。
so, you know, I guess there's a use for it.
但是，你知道，如果你只浏览一篇文章一次，然后阅读它，
But, you know, if you only go to an article once and then you read it and
然后你就再也不需要它了，这就像随机访问模式，我们
then you never need it again, and that's like a random access pattern and we
无法知道你想读什么，那么 它可能不太
can't know what you're going to want to read, then it's probably not a great
适合本地优先的软件，对吧？
fit for local-first software, right?
就像，你不是在编辑，你只是在阅读，并且你不会
Like, you're not editing, you're only reading, and you're not
返回到相同的数据。
going back to the same data.
另一方面，就像一本与之相反的食谱书，
On the other hand, like, a recipe book kind of the inverse of that, which
就像厨房经常有很多金属和射频干扰一样。
is like, kitchens often have a lot of, like, metal and RF interference.
转录 因此，即使您正在获取数据，您也可能想要
Transcribed So even though you're fetching data, you might want to
获得食谱，您希望能够回说，我去年做了什么？
have the recipe, you want to be able back say, what did I make last year?
可能是你最喜欢的食谱，你可能会在
might be your favorite recipe and you might have a little note
上面写下一些小便条。
that you've scribbled on it.
当然，我认为在食谱书的页边空白处乱涂乱画
absolutely, scribbling in the margins of your recipe books
是每个家庭的一项历史悠久的传统。
is a time honored tradition in, like, every household, I think.
所以，对，这就是回到这个问题的地方，
And so, right, like, this is where it comes back to that question,
就像，用户是否为自己获取数据，然后他们可以拥有该数据的
which is, like, is a user taking data for themself and then they can have
作者权？
authorship over it going forward?
这可能是一个很好的选择。 我认为，
It's probably a good fit.
信任越多，比如控制和信任，它们在
the more kind of like trust, like control and trust, I think are
这里是相关的，你越不能信任系统中的所有参与者
related here and the less you can trust all the participants in your
，以这种本地优先的方式构建可能就越困难。
system, the harder it probably will be to build in this local first way.
因为您需要协调通常称为身份验证的内容
Since you need to mediate what is typically referred to as auth
和典型的三层应用程序。
and your typical three tier app.
当
This needs to be thought of probably quite differently when
您构建本地优先应用程序时，可能需要以完全不同的方式来考虑这一点。
you build local first apps.
我认为这是另一天更大的谈话。
I think this is a bigger conversation for another day.
我相信本地优先的软件将提供比云服务更高的
I believe that local-first software will provide a much higher
隐私、安全和身份验证标准，
standard of privacy, security and authentication than a cloud service can,
我认为我们需要找出一大堆新的最佳实践，但这些实践
I think there's a whole bunch of new best practices that we need to figure out
可能尚未完全发现。
that might not be fully discovered yet.
是的，这绝对是一个开放的工作领域，我来这里并不是为了
yeah, it's definitely an open area of work that I'm not here to
告诉你问题已经解决了。
tell you that problem is solved.
我来这里是想告诉你，我认为这方面的潜力是巨大的
I'm here to tell you that, like, the potential, I think, is huge
，但现实是我们距离实现这一点还有很长的路要走，
for this, but the reality is we're a long way from having,
而这就是完美的。
And that's perfect.
这就是我想通过这个播客提供帮助的内容，提供一个讨论
that's what I want to help with this podcast give an outlet to discuss
这些特定领域的渠道，例如本地优先方式的身份验证是什么样的
those sort of particular areas, such as what does authentication
？
look like in a local first way?
我认为，让当地第一世界
And I think something that makes the local first world
变得如此富有的东西就是这样的。
already so rich are those like.
以这种方式构建的早期产品，我们可以分享和学习
Early products that are being built in this way where we can share and learn from
他们的经验和实验。
their experiences and their experiments.
所以我真的很期待深入探讨这些不同的主题。
So I'm really looking forward to deep dives on those various topics.
很多人都在做着伟大的工作。
tons of people doing great work.
当然，蓝天更多地以所谓的
Of course, blue skies out there doing it in more of what you'd call a
联合方式来做这件事，但他们肯定正在考虑这些问题。
federated way, but they're definitely thinking about these problems.
有很多人在开发产品。
And there's lots of people building products.
我迫不及待地想和他们谈论这些事情。
I can't wait to talk to them about this stuff.
所以再退一步。
So going a step back again.
当您说到同步时，我会想到
When you say synchronization, I'm thinking the Dropbox icon back in the
我经常使用 Dropbox 时的 Dropbox 图标。
days when I was using Dropbox a lot.
这样就实现了同步。
So that does synchronization.
我想很多人对此还是很熟悉的。
I think a lot of people are still familiar with that.
这有点像我的思维模式吗？
Is that kind of like the mental model, how I think about it?
Git 也有一个概念。
Git also has a notion of.
同步，如果用推和拉更明确一点的话，我将如何对
Synchronizing, if a bit more explicit with push and pull how would I do that
我的数据进行同步，在我考虑我的数据时，也许更多地在 SQL 表方面。
for my data where I think about my data, maybe more in terms of SQL tables.
那么，我如何将这种非常直观的同步模型转化为
So how do I translate that very intuitive model of syncing to the
我的应用程序更严酷的现实，
more harsh realities of my app,
这是一个很棒的手电筒，可以像世界已经发生的变化一样发光，对吗？
This is a great flashlight to shine on like how the world has changed, right?
那么，如果您查看Dropbox，您会发现 Dropbox 同步什么？
So if you go and look at Dropbox, what does Dropbox sync?
它同步文件。
It syncs files.
你的机器上的 git repo 是什么？
What is a git repo on your machine?
git 存储库是一堆文件。
A git repo is a bunch of files.
然后 git 和 Dropbox 都会在幕后做一些特殊的事情来将这些
And then git and Dropbox both do something special behind the scenes to get those
文件从其他地方或其他地方获取。
files other places or from other places.
好的。
Okay.
什么是 Google 文档？
What is a Google Doc?
您的计算机上有 Google 文档，但您实际上并没有它。
You have a Google Doc on your computer, you don't actually have it.
你只是看看而已，对吧？
You're just looking at it, right?
这就是为什么谷歌可以丢弃你所有的数据，因为
And that's why Google can throw away all your data because there have
其他人进行了太多的编辑。
been too many edits by other people.
没关系在飞机上花三个小时重写
Nevermind spending three hours on a flight, rewriting
愚蠢的博客文章，对吧？
the stupid blog post, right?
因为，你没有，我没有医生。
Cause it's, you didn't, I didn't have the doc.
我有一个缓存。
I had a cache.
我有一份副本。
I had a copy.
我有一个看法。
I had a view.
因为其他人编辑了它，所以实际的文档、地方已经
And because somebody else had edited it, the actual doc, the place had
改变，而我的现在变成了垃圾。
changed and mine was now trash.
。  Google 文档是地方。
. Google Docs are places.
我认为这就像一种非常有趣的二元性，对吧？
And I think this is like a really interesting kind of duality, right?
因为我们需要文档的这两个属性。
Because we want both Properties for our documents.
我希望能够向某人发送链接，以便他们
I want to be able to send a link to someone so that they
可以与我一起编辑文档。
can edit a document with me.
正确的？
Right?
感觉就像一个地方。
That feels like a place.
但我也希望能够保存一份副本并通过电子邮件发送出去，或者
But I also want to be able to save a copy and email it around or
将其放在我的计算机上并查看它并知道它是我的。
have it on my computer and look at it and know that it's mine.
正确的？
Right?
因此，我们想要这种类似对象的属性，就像
So we want properties of both this kind of like object like
我们从文件中获得的体验一样。
experience that we get from files.
以及我们从云文档中获得的类似经验的地方。
And the place like experience we get from cloud documents.
我认为这就是我们
And I think that's where we get into like a real fundamental
两者之间真正产生根本紧张关系的地方。
tension between the two.
您认为我们日常使用的任何软件是否
Do you feel any sort of software that we use on a daily basis is getting
最接近您认为可以很好地解决紧张局势的软件？
the closest to what you think could be a good resolution of the tension?
我认为有很多公司已经取得了渐进式的进步。
I think there are lots of companies that have made incremental progress.
只是想谈谈一些范例。
Just to kind of, you know, speak to some exemplars.
我的意思是，显然，我认为应用程序背后的基本思想通常是
I mean, obviously, I think the basic idea behind an app generally, I think it's
有问题的，即它获取您的数据并将其放入他们的应用程序中。
kind of problematic, which is it's taking your data and putting it into their app.
所以你无法访问某个地方，只能在其他地方访问它。
So you can't access somewhere, access it anywhere else.
Apple Notes 也是一个很好的例子。
Great example, again, is Apple Notes.
或多或少是纯文本笔记，但你无法在 VS code 或记事本或
Plain text notes, more or less, but you can't open them in VS code or notepad or
其他任何东西或 Dropbox 笔记中打开它们，对吗？
anything else or Dropbox notes, right?
例如，我们已经成功地将文本注释转换为
Like, we've managed to turn text notes into closed proprietary formats that are
特定于单个软件的封闭专有格式。
specific to a single piece of software.
这真是太糟糕了。
That's sort of a bummer.
您无法将Apple Notes 与 Dropbox 同步。
You can't sync your Apple Notes with Dropbox.
但是好吧，我仍然认为，在这个
But okay, I still think though that, like, within this world
文件与你知道的世界中，事物与地点，文件与链接。
of files versus You know, things versus places, files versus links.
苹果笔记就像一个很好的中间地带，对吗？
Apple notes is like a nice middle ground, right?
就像您可以做笔记一样，它始终可以离线工作，但您可以
Like you can make a note, it always works offline, but you can share
与其他人共享它们并查看编辑内容并从人们那里获取更新。
them with other people and see the edits and get updates from people.
所以这真的很酷。
So that's really cool.
我认为 Figma 正在用类似的
I think Figma is doing really interesting things with like,
分支和去中心化工作流程做一些非常有趣的事情。
branches and decentralized workflows.
如果你曾经与在使用 Figma 的大型组织中工作的人交谈过，你就会知道，
If you ever talk to people who work in a large org that uses Figma, You know,
存在这样一个问题，那就是当你在早期阶段进行设计时
there's this problem, which is that like when you're working on a design in
，你不希望其他人看到 你的工作，对吗？
the early stages, you don't want other people to look at your work, right?
他们不希望有人跳进来走，我不喜欢那种颜色。
You're they don't want someone hopping in and going, I don't like that color.
就像，是的，我还没完成。
It's like, yeah, I'm not done.
稍后再回来吧？
back later, right?
您想要可以探索的创造性隐私。
You want that creative privacy where you can explore.
因此人们找到了所有这些创造性的方法来在 Figma 中构建它。
And so people have found all these creative ways to build that in Figma.
我认为组织上对此有所认识。
And I think there's somewhat cognizant of that organizationally.
所以我认为这是一个很好的例子。
So I think that's like a good example of yeah.
就像试图探索其中一些深度一样，我认为，在大多数
Like trying to plumb some of those depths, I think, though, for the most
情况下，我的意思是，你知道，我们可以给谷歌文档一点功劳，对吗？
part, I mean, you know, we could give a bit of credit to Google Docs, right?
就像，是的，它需要浏览器扩展程序，并且
Like, yes, it requires a browser extension and like literally half the
至少是您乘坐航班的一半时间。
time that you at least I get on a flight.
我意识到，虽然我安装了浏览器扩展插件，但它的
I realized that although I had the browser extension plug installed, it was in
配置文件错误，或者我不记得兑现文档或其他什么，但
the wrong profile, or I didn't remember to cash the document or whatever, but
您至少可以从 Google Docs 获得一些类似的离线支持。
you can at least get some semblance of that offline support from Google Docs.
当然，你知道，Git 也是一个典范，就像
And of course, you know, Git is an exemplar as well in terms of, like,
Git 加上 GitHub 给你带来的东西一样。
Git plus GitHub gives you something.
它很笨重。
It's clunky.
我在这里并不是要告诉您 Git 具有出色的用户体验，但是，您知道，Git 为
I'm not here to tell you Git's a great user experience, but, you know, Git
您提供了在两个世界中工作的能力，您可以
gives you this ability to work kind of in both worlds where you can share
通过 GitHub 共享文件链接，但您可以拥有该文件的完整副本。 存储库
links to files through GitHub, but you can have a full copy of the repository
及其在您计算机上的历史记录。
with its history on your machine.
正确的。
Right.
是的。
Yes.
我认为从用户体验的角度来看，还有很多东西需要探索，
I think there's a lot to be explored from a user experience perspective,
比如适合
like patterns that fit the domain of the software patterns that
用户直观地使用的软件模式领域的模式。
users intuitively can work with.
但我认为，就我们如何实际构建而言，可能还有很
But I think in terms of how we actually building that there's probably still
长的路要走，并且我认为已经有公司在推进，这是非常非常幸运的
a long way to go and think it's super, super fortunate that there are
。
companies already pushing forward.
无论是 Figma 还是 Google的 Google Docs，甚至是 Notion，我
there whether it being Figma or Google with Google Docs or even Notion who I
认为在同步方面并不是非常复杂，但它仍然是一个很好的
think is like not super sophisticated in terms of syncing is yet a good
例子，说明在构建在同步方面不是超细粒度的协作软件时您可以走多远。
example of like how far you can get while building collaborative software
它的同步分辨率。
that is not super fine granular in terms of its syncing resolution.
所以我认为无论是在用户体验方面，同步都将是一个持续的话题。
So I think syncing will be a continuous topic both in terms of user experience.
然后当你真正开始实施时，当你说
And then when you actually get to the implementation, when you're saying
同步时，我已经看到术语 CRDT与本地优先有相当多的联系。
syncing I've already seen the term CRDT quite a bit associated with local first.
您能简单介绍一下 CRDT 是什么吗？
Can you briefly touch on what CRDTs are?
我们可能没有足够的时间来充分探讨它。
We probably don't have enough time to fully go into it.
也许可以，
Maybe you can,
让我们提供一个非常高水平的入门知识。
let's give a very high level primer.
我认为这是一个需要深入探讨的主题，但
I think this is a topic that needs a deeper dive, but
我们将进行快速介绍。
we'll give the quick intro.
因此 CRDT 背后的想法是它代表
So the idea behind the CRDT is that it stands for a conflict
无冲突复制数据类型。
free replicated data type.
数据类型非常简单。
data type is pretty easy.
有很多不同的 CRDT。
There are lots of different CRDTs.
你可以有一个集合，你可以有一个数组，你可以有一个计数器。
You can have a set, you can have an array, you can have a counter.
我们正在开发一个基本上类似于 JSON 文件的文件。
We work on one that's basically like a JSON file.
正确的？
Right?
所以它有集合、数组、计数器、地图等东西，
So it has sets and arrays and counters and maps and things
当你说数据类型时，这就是我现在用来构建我的应用程序的东西。
and when you say data type, this is now a thing that I'm using to build my app.
因此，以同样的方式，如果我构建一个JavaScript 应用程序并且我将使用映射
So in the same way, if I build a JavaScript app and I would use a map
或设置数组，那么现在我将使用其中一个CRDT 作为我的数据的基础。
or set an array, now I would use one of those CRDTs as foundation for my data.
你为什么要这么做？
Why are you doing that?
嗯，因为它是复制的。
Well, because it's replicated.
是什么意思？
What does means?
这意味着您可以采用该数据类型并将其发送到一堆
It means you can take that data type and you can send it to a
不同的计算机。
bunch of different computers.
好吧，酷。
All right, cool.
典型的 JavaScript 地图无法做到这一点。
typical JavaScript map can't do that.
是的，我的意思是，你可以调用 toJSON然后将其发布到某个地方。
Yeah, I mean, you can call toJSON and then post it somewhere.
这将我们引向描述的最后一部分，这是无冲突的。
And that leads us to the last part of the description, which is conflict free.
这就是繁重的工作完成的地方。
And that's where the heavy work gets done.
因此，只要您
So replicating your data is not that hard as long as you
不关心数据会发生什么，复制数据并不难。
don't care what happens to it.
我不知道，你可以打开你的窗户，然后开始对着窗户大喊，
You could just, I don't know, open your window and start shouting,
你知道，字节码。
you know, byte codes at the window.
从技术上讲，我想，如果有人在听的话，你正在复制它。
Technically, you're replicating it, I guess, if anybody's listening.
但你知道，无冲突部分才是棘手的地方。
But you know, the conflict free part, that's where it gets tricky.
您如何确保如果两个人都编辑文档，第一，
How do you make sure that if two people both edit the document, One,
您可以合并更改，但第二，不会丢失任何内容，对吗？
that you can merge the changes, but two, that nothing's lost, right?
就像，如果你只是说，好吧，我要扔掉，
Like, it's really easy to merge data if you just say, well, I'm going to throw,
总是扔掉你的数据并保留我的数据，那么合并数据真的很容易。
always throw away your data and keep mine.
但这不是一个非常有用的策略，对吗？
But that's not a very useful strategy, right?
因此 CRDT 背后的整个想法是许多不同的方法。
So the whole idea behind CRDTs is lots of different approaches.
大量不同的实现。
Tons of different implementations.
这是一个非常活跃的研究领域，目前仍有许多伟大的想法正在
It's a very active area of research and there's lots of great ideas
涌现。 从
still unfolding out there right now.
概念上讲，这非常简单，就像，如果两个人
And it's really simple conceptually though, which is like, if two people
编辑一个东西，你应该能够将他们的编辑合并在一起，并且都
edit a thing, you should be able to merge their edits together and both
得到相同的答案，而不必求助于中央机构。
get the same answer without having to go to recourse to a central authority.
这似乎是一个非常有趣的领域，我想了解更多。
That seems like a very interesting area that I want to learn more about.
当考虑 CRDT 时，我会想到一些技术，无论
When thinking about CRDTs, there are a few technologies that come to mind, whether
是 Kevin Jans 的 Yjs，他已经在这方面工作了很多年，
that's being Yjs by Kevin Jans, who's been working on this already for many years,
然后你们都在研究自动合并。 因此，我很想了解更多
then you all been working on auto merge . So I would love to learn a lot more
有关这些的信息，但现在我们将把它搁置起来，并说，好吧，
about those, but right now we'll shelve it away and say, okay, CRDTs is a great
如果您需要实现同步，CRDT 是一个很好的策略。
strategy if you need to implement syncing.
是的
Is that
，是的，我认为有一些，我不太相信
Yeah, it is, and I think there's a couple of, I'm not a big believer
灵丹妙药或类似技术的神奇思维。
in silver bullets or kind of like magical thinking with technology.
这里有一系列的权衡，对吧？
There's a set of tradeoffs here, right?
例如，当 git 发生冲突时会发生什么？
Like, what happens when you have a conflict in git?
好吧，你正在打开你的文本编辑器，连续寻找一堆小于号，
Well, you're busting open your text editor and looking for a bunch of less than signs
并希望在再次推送愚蠢的提交之前找到它们。
in a row and hoping you found them all before you push the stupid commit again.
您知道，类似地，CRDT通常不会出现这个问题，但
You know, similarly, CRDTs don't generally have that problem, but
仍然可能会出现冲突，对吗？
you can still have conflicts, right?
就像你和我都编辑文档标题一样，CRDT 无法
Like if you and I both edit the title of a document, You know, the CRDT isn't going
知道哪一个是正确的。
to be able to know which one is right.
因此，这里存在一些有趣的挑战，这些挑战超越了
So there's interesting, just like, challenges here that go beyond,
抽象的计算机科学问题。
abstract computer science problems.
这是一个非常根本的问题。
This is a really fundamental problem.
计算机无法知道标题应该是什么，对吗？
The computer can't know what the title should be, right?
在中央云模型中，会发生的情况是，我们中的一个人会
And in the central cloud model, what happens is, like, one of us will find
在我们去写的时候发现我们输了。
out when we go to write that we lost.
所以你知道问题马上就会发生。
And so you know the problem happens right away.
因此，CRDT 与用户体验设计问题一样有趣的原因在于，
And so what makes CRDTs interesting from like a user experience design problem is
您可以在距离它们
that you can have conflicts discovered a long way away from where they're
创建的地方很远的地方（无论是在空间上还是在时间上）发现冲突。 这
created, either in space or in time.
实际上会带来严重的用户体验后果。
And so that actually has serious user experience consequences.
这也可能发生在你身上并且是正确的。
This can also happen to you and get right.
就像我们所有在这里聆听的开发人员一样，都知道那是什么感觉。
Like all of us developers listening here know what it's like.
例如，尝试合并一个长期运行的分支，然后意识到
To, like, try and merge a long running branch and realize that
其他人完全重写了您编辑的文件，然后
somebody else has, like, completely rewritten a file you edited and
您会想，哦不，我该怎么办？
you're like, oh no, what do I do?
我是否可以放弃整个一周的工作并重新开始？
Do I just throw my entire week of working away and start over?
或者我会说，
Or do I, like,
天下没有免费的午餐。
There's no free lunch here.
所以它在语义上分歧很大或者变化很大，那么
So it's semantically diverges a lot or changes a lot, then the
用户仍然需要帮忙。
user still needs to help out.
同样，CRDT 实际上无法识别所有冲突，对吧？
And similarly, the CRDT can't actually recognize all the conflicts, right?
我们可以捕捉到的技术冲突。
The technical conflicts we can catch.
但同样，如果你考虑一下软件，Git
But again, if you sort of think about software, Git is kind of
在某些方面有点像一个糟糕的 CRDT。
like a bad CRDT in some ways.
即使我们编辑不同的文件，也不意味着测试会
Even if we edit different files, that doesn't mean the tests will
通过或者软件会有用。
pass or the software will be useful.
我可能已经重命名了您正在使用的函数。
I may have renamed a function that you were using.
两者都可以干净地提交，但是当我们尝试运行测试时，它
Both can commit cleanly, but then when we try and run the tests, it
甚至无法解析并且崩溃。
won't even parse and it crashes.
我们可以考虑所有这些事情，我认为这就是问题的设计方面
We can think about all those things, and I think that's the, design side of the
，然后，在实现方面有很多巧妙的东西可以讨论
problem, and then, there's lots of neat stuff to talk about on the implementation
，但我们现在可以从这里开始。
side, but we can on from that for now.
我们稍后再讨论这些。
We'll back to those later.
是的，除了同步和CRDT 之外，显然这是一个非常
Yeah, so going beyond syncing and CRDTs, obviously that's a very
重要的方面，同步通常用于构建本地优先的软件，
important aspect, syncing in general for building local-first software,
因为它是支柱之一，就像软件应该在我的设备上运行一样，
as it's one of the pillars, like the software should work on my device,
我们应该能够协作。
and we should be able to collaborate.
那么如果我们回到过去。
So if we come back to the.
该软件应该在我的设备上运行。
the software should run on my device.
通常
Which sort of problems does a developer who's typically rather
构建三层 Web 应用程序的开发人员会遇到哪些类型的问题，
building that three tier web app, what sort of new problems does the
开发人员现在需要考虑哪些类型的新问题，或者
developer now need to think about or maybe think about differently aside
如果您想首先在本地构建下一个应用程序，那么除了同步之外，可能需要考虑不同的问题 方式。
from syncing if you want to build your next app in a local first way.
最大的一个是建筑学。
The biggest one is architectural.
当你在这种环境中长大时你就会知道，
When you grow up in this environment of you know, the
数据库是事实的来源。
database is the source of truth.
然后事情就开始发展了，你知道，现在你遇到了不同的问题。
And then things sort of roll out, you know, now you have different problems.
比如，当我的用户离线时，我如何确保我拥有数据？
Like, how do I make sure that I have the data, you know, when my user is offline?
我能否确保我已获取他们需要的所有内容，以便
Can I make sure that I've fetched everything they need so that
他们在离线之前知道？
they know before they go offline?
就像，是的，你是最新的。
Like, yes, you're up to date.
同样，你知道，如果你可以部分在线，对吗？
Similarly, you know, if you can be partially online, right?
就像，也许您在线并且可以与同步服务器通信。
Like, maybe you're online and you can talk to the sync server.
但别人不能。
But somebody else can't.
所以，您知道，您怎么知道您正在看到其他人
So, you know, how can you know that you're seeing what other people
正在看到的内容以及您正在看到其他人发送的内容，对吗？
are seeing that you're seeing the things somebody else has sent, right?
当我们谈论这些东西时，我喜欢举一些现场的例子。
I like to give examples from the field when we talk about this stuff.
Facebook Messenger 是这个问题的一个非常简单的版本，
Facebook Messenger has like a really simple version of this problem, you
当你使用手机离线时，你仍然可以回复消息，但
can still reply to a message when you're offline with your phone, but
你不会看到一个小复选框，上面写着“是的，消息已发送”。
you don't get the little checkbox that says, Yep, that's been sent.
直到其他人拿出手机并查看它，
And it's not until somebody else takes the phone out and looks at it
并且微型头像图标下降到消息下方时，
and the little, you know, miniature avatar icon drops below the message
您才知道他们已经看到了它。
that you know that they've seen it.
这对于源代码意味着什么？
What does that mean for source code?
或者像文本文档一样。
Or like a text document.
我的意思是，我们不能只是将头像移动到页面底部，对吗？
I mean, we can't just move the avatar to the bottom of the page, right?
因此，这里存在一些非常有趣的挑战，以
So there's like really interesting challenges here around kind of,
不同的方式思考如何构建应用程序，对吗？
thinking a little differently about how you build your app, right?
同样，仅仅因为您在本地拥有数据或可以
And similarly, just because you have the data locally or could
在本地拥有数据并不意味着它会快速加载。
have the data locally doesn't mean that it's going to load quickly.
如果您将所有内容存储为索引数据库中的长编辑日志，则
If you store everything as like a long log of edits in an indexed DB,
加载时间可能比从网络获取它要花费更长的时间。
it could take you longer to load than if you were fetching it from the web.
所以我们需要对这些事情深思熟虑。
So we need to be very thoughtful about these things.
但使用这种方法的结果有一个真正致命的好处，我
But the result of Using this approach has one really killer benefit that I
每天仍然对此感到高兴，那就是，你知道，有一个老东西
just still delight in every day, which is that, you know, there's the old thing
，你知道，它在我的机器上运行。
about, you know, it ran on my machine.
好吧，我们将运送您的机器。
Well, we'll ship your machine.
Docker 就是这样诞生的，对吗？
And that's how Docker was born, right?
不过，这有点像本地优先软件，如果
Like, it's sort of like that, though, with local-first software, like, if
它可以在您的计算机上运行，​​那么这就是目标部署环境。
it works on your machine, like, that's the target deployment environment.
你拥有一切。
You have the whole thing.
所以你就完成了。
So you're done.
正确的？
Right?
就像，只要你在某个地方有一个同步服务器，你就完成了。
Like, as long as you have a sync server somewhere, you're finished.
事实上，也许这是一个好时刻。
And actually, maybe this is a good moment.
我可以谈谈点对点吗？
Can I talk a little bit about peer to peer for a sec?
请。
Please.
是的。
Yes.
所以，我认为我从人们那里听到的一个误解是，哦，本地第一。
So, I think one misconception I hear from people is like, Oh, local first.
这意味着您反对云并且不喜欢服务器。
That means you're anti cloud and you don't like servers.
一点也不。
Not at all.
比如，点对点技术很有趣，而且在某些
Like, peer to peer technologies are interesting and there have been You
用例中，它们对于实现用户目标非常重要，比如，
know, use cases where they were really vital to achieving users aims, like, you
当你想下载完整的 Linux ISO 专辑时，你知道，然后是
know, when you want to download an entire album full of Linux ISOs, you know, then
BitTorrent 真的很好，你可以明白为什么拥有中央服务器
BitTorrent is, like, really good, and you can see why having central servers
会成为一个问题，但就大多数软件而言，你知道，
would be a problem for that, but in the case of most software, you know, one,
点对点系统实际上在很多情况下都不能很好地工作 网络条件。
peer to peer systems actually don't work very well in a lot of network conditions.
你可以，你知道，你可以通过一些工作或 VPN 在你的家庭网络上运行 BitTorrent
You can, you know, you can run BitTorrent on your home network with a little
，但在咖啡店或类似的地方，那些
bit of work or a VPN, but at the coffee shop or places like that, those peer
点对点系统真的很困难，因为网络往往配置为
to peer systems really struggle because the network tends to be configured in
这不允许他们工作。
a way that doesn't allow them to work.
但还不止这些，对吧？
But more than that, right?
就像，如果你和我正在合作开发一个点对点系统，对吧？
Like, if you and I are collaborating on a peer to peer system, right?
就像，我大部分时间都在使用笔记本电脑。
Like, I'm on a laptop most of the time.
我不希望我的工作仅仅因为我合上盖子就完全消失，
I don't want my work to disappear completely just because I close the lid,
我们需要服务器。
We want servers.
我们希望他们是
We want them
认真的，他们确实应该为我们服务。
mean, they literally should serve us.
他们是对的，而不是我们为他们服务，对吗？
They right, not us serving them, right?
我们试图让服务器为我们服务，而不是相反。
We're trying to make the server serve us rather than vice versa.
爱它。
Love it.
那太棒了。
That's great.
所以，是的，这个模型的最大区别是你仍然需要
And so, yeah, the big difference here in this model is that you still want
服务器，但他们的责任是公正的。
servers, but their responsibility is just.
托管数据并分发它。
to host data and distribute it.
所以，你知道，是的，你想要它。
And so, you know, yeah, you want it.
它需要在线才能成功，因为
It needs to be online for things to be successful because peer to
点对点系统并不能真正发挥作用。
peer systems don't really work.
我花了很多年的时间尝试采用点对点架构，
I have spent many years trying to like adopt peer to peer architecture
然后才最终屈服并接受这种观点。
before kind of finally giving in and embracing this perspective.
即使它们确实有效，也不能解决问题，也就是说，
And then even if they do work, they don't solve the problem, which is
事实上，即使你不正确，你也希望你的数据在线
that in fact, you want your data to be online even when you're not
。
Right.
你知道，
You know,
它可以发挥一个有趣的作用。
there's an interesting role it can play.
我认识一些人还没有放弃点对点。
I know a few folks who haven't given up yet on peer to peer.
也许在它确实有效的情况下，它可以是该过程的可选部分。
And maybe in the cases where it does work, it can be an optional part of the process.
对于技术堆栈，假设您处于智能家居环境中，您
Of a technology stack, let's say you're in a smart home setting where you
可以假设软件的工作原理。
can assumptions about software works.
嗯，对等软件很棒，并且可以很好地工作，但是，我还没有
Well, peer to peer software is great and can work really well, but it, I have not
看到对等系统的设计或实现，它
seen a design or implementation of peer to peer systems that are like really
在所有网络环境中都非常强大，而且您实际上并没有几个网络环境。
robust in all network environments and where you don't just actually have a few
集中式服务器隐藏在舞台之外。
centralized servers hiding off stage.
虽然你说的是点对点，但实际上，你知道，20% 的
While you're saying peer to peer, but actually, you know, 20 percent of
流量会流向某个服务器，就像WebRTC 一样，对吧？
traffic is going to some server like a great example here is WebRTC, right?
如果您熟悉 WebRTC，人们会认为它就像浏览器
If you're familiar with WebRTC, people think of it as like this
中内置的点对点系统，但这不是有两个原因。
peer to peer system built into the browser, but it's not for two reasons.
第一的。
First.
虽然 WebRTC 确实允许两台计算机直接相互通信，但
While it is true that WebRTC allows two computers to talk directly to each other,
为​​了让它们了解彼此并进行对话，
in order for them to find out about each other to have that conversation,
您需要一台服务器来介绍它们。
you need a server to introduce them.
第二个是，对于这种情况的普遍性，人们有不同的看法，但我
The second is that, and opinions vary about the prevalence of this, but I have
看到过可靠的报告，大约 20% 的 WebRTC
seen credible reports that are sort of on the order of 20 percent of WebRTC
连接无法进行点对点连接。
connections, cannot be made peer to peer.
相反，它们是通过所谓的转向服务器发送的，该服务器
And are instead sent through what's called a turn server, which is just relay
只是为您反弹流量的中继。 这
that just bounces the traffic for you.
并不是说 WebRTC 不好。
And like, that's not to say WebRTC is bad.
我的意思是，它非常有用。
I mean, it's super useful.
我们每天都会在视频会议等生活中使用它。
We use it every day in our, like, video conferencing lives.
但这并不真的像点对点。
But that, it's not really like peer to peer.
它就像具有可用的对等快速路径的客户端服务器。
It's like client server with a peer to peer fast path when it's available.
我认为还有很多值得探索的地方。
I think there's lots to be explored as well.
这更像是在网络方面。
That's more like on the networking side.
我认为取决于某些用例，例如 . 假设您
And I think depending on for some use cases, like . Let's say you
为仓库或游轮等构建软件。
build software for a warehouse or maybe a cruise ship or something.
我认为那里可能有真正的用例，而且我真的
I think there, there might be real use cases, and I'm really
可以控制......
you have control...
正在探索它。
are exploring it.
是的，如果你可以控制网络，你完全可以，实际上
Yeah, if you have control over the network, you totally can and actually
我们的朋友在同上，前实验室合作者 Ray McKelvey 工作的地方已经
our friends at ditto where former lab collaborator Ray McKelvey works have
建立了一个非常伟大的业务，使用与
built a really great business building local-first software using a different
我们用于飞机的 CRDT 不同类型的 CRDT 构建本地优先软件和喜欢快餐店。
kind of CRDT than the one we use for airplanes and like fast food restaurants.
他们已经像真正的规模化生产一样，
They have like real scaled out production, industrial deployments
在该领域进行了该技术的工业部署。
of this technology in the field.
从各方面来看，你知道，它运行得非常好。
And by all accounts, you know, it's working really well.
因此，如果您现在用 Google 搜索“本地优先”，您可能会看到您作为
So if you Google Local First right now, you might come across the blog post
合著者的博客文章和文章，其中您首次介绍了
and essay that you've been a co author of where you first introduce the ideas
本地优先的想法，并且作为其中的一部分，您有本地优先的七个理想 第一的。
of Local First, and as part of it, you have those seven ideals of Local First.
所以我认为这足以填满一整集来真正
So I think this would be enough to, fill an entire episode on to really
公正地实现每个理想，但也许你可以总结一下这七个
do each ideal justice, but maybe you can just Summarize those seven
理想以及它们对你意味着什么。
ideals and what they mean for you.
是的。
Yeah.
好吧，我们已经讨论过很多关于构建本地优先
Well, we've talked a bunch already about how building local-first
软件对开发人员有何好处，对吧？
software is good for developers, right?
比如，你的分销成本会更好。
Like, your distribution costs are better.
您的随叫随到体验会更好。 希望
Your on call experience is better.
您的软件不那么复杂。
Your software is less complicated, hopefully.
但是，开发“本地优先”理念背后的最初动机
But the original motivation behind developing the ideas of local first was
实际上是关注用户体验的类型，而不是
really focused on kind of user experience and not in the sort of what corner
按钮的圆角半径或号召性用语的绿色阴影，而是像
radius should the buttons be or what shade of green for the call to action, but like
真正的核心体验一样 用户正在使用您的软件。
the real core experience that the user has a person who's consuming your software.
因此，我们与马丁·克莱普曼、亚当·威金斯和
And so we identified with Martin Kleppmann and Adam Wiggins and
马克·麦格拉纳根确定了七个理想。
Mark McGranagan seven ideals.
我们认为本地优先的软件应该追求第一个，那就是
That we think local-first software should aspire to the first one is no
下一帧没有旋转器，或者你的退款，就像你永远不应该去打开
spinners right next frame or your money back like you should never go to open
某些东西，只是看到像旋转器一样，因为你的网络连接
something and just see like a spinner because your network connection is
不好或其他类似的事情就是这样 不可原谅的是，我们拥有
bad or whatever else like that's just it's inexcusable we have the fastest
历史上最快的计算机，拥有有史以来最大的驱动器和最大的带宽，就像我们无法获得
computers in history with the biggest drives ever in the most bandwidth like
自己的个人数据一样，这是可笑的。
it's just ludicrous that our own personal data would not be available to us.
第二，你的工作不会被困在一台设备上。
Number two your work is not trapped on one device.
没有人愿意生活在这样一个世界：你把手机从悬崖上
No one wants to be in a world where like you dropped your phone, over a cliff
或壁架上掉下来，然后突然间你的数据就全部消失了，对吗？
or off a ledge or whatever and suddenly your data is all gone with it, right?
您将笔记本电脑落在火车上，现在您失去了毕生的工作。
You left your laptop on the train and now you've lost your life's work.
不，我们不想要这样。
No, we don't want that.
因此，您的工作应该能够在所有设备之间同步，
So your work should be able to synchronize across all your devices
并且在每个设备上都可用。
and be available on every device.
同时还有没有旋转器的想法，对吧？ 我们的
Simultaneously with this idea of not having spinners, right?
想法是我们希望所有这七件事都成为现实。
The idea is we want all seven of these things to be true together.
第三点是网络是可选的。
Number three is that the network is optional.
正如我们所讨论的，您经常会发现自己处于网络
As we've discussed, like, you often find yourself in places where the network
由于技术原因而无法使用的地方，或者只是因为
either is not available because of technical reasons, or just because,
您想要离线。
you know, you want to be offline.
正确的。
Right.
做出这样的选择，关闭
There's something to be said for making that choice, turning off
Wi-Fi 信号，保持专注，并且仍然能够工作，是有道理的。
the Wi Fi signal, staying focused, and still being able to work.
我们仍然坚持与您的同事无缝协作。
We still insist on seamless collaboration with your colleagues.
那是第四个，对吧？
That's number four, right?
如果不是协作的话，它只是本地的，而不是本地优先的。
It's, if it's not collaborative, it's local only, not local first.
我认为另一个非常重要的概念是
Another one that I think is really important is this notion,
第五个概念，即现在。
number five, the long now.
我可以使用一张微型 SD 卡。
I can get on a single micro SD card.
就像超级任天堂发布的每一款游戏一样。
Like, every game that was ever released for Super Nintendo.
这些将在一百年后发挥作用。
And those will work a hundred years from now.
比如，您在职业生涯中构建的软件有多少在一
Like, how much of the software that you've built in your career
百年后仍然可以使用？ 十年后，其中有
will work a hundred years from now?
多少仍然存在？
How much of it will still be around ten years from now?
对于我们许多人来说，我们的大部分工作就这样消失了。
For many of us, so much of our work just evaporates.
这不仅仅是为了希望看到你的作品生存下来的虚荣心。
And it's not just for the vanity of wanting to see your work survive.
当你与人交谈、写书，或者……
When you're talking to people, writing books, or...
你知道，那些把自己的职业生涯当作一个长期
You know, who have built their careers around like a long term
项目的人，你知道，为一本书做研究可能需要 10 年。 有
project, you know, it could take 10 years to do the research for a book.
多少10 年前的云服务仍然存在？
How many cloud services that were around 10 years ago are still around?
或者说，今天存在的有多少在 10 年后还会存在。
Or how many of that are around today will be around in 10 years.
你知道，你无法控制谁会被收购或被关闭。
You know, you can't control who's going to get acquired or shut down.
所以我认为这是其中很重要的一部分。
So I think that's a big part of it.
第六点是默认的安全和隐私。
Number six is security and privacy by default.
你知道，为什么默认情况下，当我使用软件时，公司的产品经理
You know, why is the default that when I use software, the product managers at
或支持人员可以随时读取我的数据？
the company or the support people can just read my data whenever they want?
我的意思是，他们没有。
I mean, they don't.
我希望他们不会。
I hope they don't.
他们大多数...
They most...
地方说他们不会，
Places say they won't,
对吧。
Right.
但你知道，他们，他们可以，对吧。
but you know, they, they could, right.
这真是一团糟。
That's pretty messed up.
第七，最终，我们希望用户
And then number seven, ultimately, you know, we want the users to
保留所有权和控制权。
retain ownership and control.
正确的。 从
Right.
某种意义上说，这是对
And that's in some sense, kind of a distillation and restating of
其他一些观点的提炼和重申，但类似。
some of the other points, but like.
你知道，如果有人能把它从你身边夺走，那它就不是你的了。
You know, if someone can take it away from you, it's not yours.
我们希望您能够通过该软件来决定
We want you to be able to have the software to make decisions
何时更新。
about when you update it.
如果您更新它，您与谁共享您的数据，何时与
If you update it, who you share your data with, when you share
他们共享您的数据并将这些工具交到用户手中。
your data with them and to put those tools into the user's hands.
我们希望他们有这种感觉。
We want them to have that feeling.
这是拥有该事物并拥有代理权和所有权的真实事实。
It's a genuine fact of having the thing and having agency and ownership over.
这就是七个理想。
those are the seven ideals.
我认为它与许多开发人员的好处相吻合，对吧？
I think it dovetails with a lot of the developer benefits, right?
就像，让
Like, sort of the same underlying decisions that make things
开发人员的事情变得更容易的相同的基本决策也可以改善用户的事情。
easier for developers also can improve things for users.
但这就是七个理想。
But those are the seven ideals.
我想说，从产品的角度和最终用户的角度来看，我认为
I would say from a product perspective and from the end user perspective, I think
这没有什么争议。
there's nothing controversial about it.
我认为，就像今天几乎所有为云构建应用程序的开发人员一样，他们
I think like almost all developers who build apps for the cloud today would
可能仍然会说，是的，这些对于我们的应用程序来说是很棒的特性。
probably still say, yes, those would be great characteristics for our apps.
很难像云优先那样构建具有
It's just hard to build apps like in a cloud first way that have
所有这些特征的应用程序。
all of those characteristics.
所以我认为这就是为什么我们需要一些不同的模型，即如何构建软件。
So I think this is why we need a bit of a different model, how to build software.
而且，从用户的角度来看，这些都是令人惊叹的。
And, those from a user perspective are amazing.
从开发人员的角度来看，一切变得更
And from a developer perspective, everything becoming
简单听起来令人难以置信。
simpler sounds incredible.
缩小一点，我喜欢本地优先的所有想法，所以这不是
Zooming out a bit, I love all the ideas of Local First, and so this is not the
今天节目的主题，就像，在过去的两年里，我
topic of today's show like, I'm also, for the last two years, working on a
自己也在开发本地优先应用程序，但是，假装我' 早两年，只是想
Local First app myself, but, Pretending I'd be two years earlier and just trying
弄清楚什么是本地第一？
to make sense of what is local first?
那是给我的吗？
Is that for me?
我该怎么办？
How do I go about it?
假设我正处于我的旅程的开始阶段，我会向您作为
Let's say I'm at the beginning of my journey and I'd be asking you as
其他构建者寻求建议，例如，嘿，本地首先准备好让我
a fellow builder for advice, like, Hey, Is local first ready for me
今天用它构建我的下一个应用程序了吗？
to build my next app with it today?
如果是的话，我的典型路径是什么样的？ 已经
And if so what does my typical path look like?
有类似 Ruby onRails 的工具了吗？
Is there like a Ruby on Rails for it already?
这适合我吗？
Is this a good fit for me?
我是否宁愿像一个喜欢冒险的探险家？
Do I rather have to be like an adventurous explorer?
或者我是否可以以
Or can I already go into this with a mindset of what
最流行的堆栈的心态来讨论这个问题？
is the most popular stack?
这也是我在这里必须采用的，
And that's also what I got to adopt here,
所以我们将在 2023 年记录这一点。
So we're recording this in 2023.
今天我想说，构建本地第一个 Web 应用程序可能
And today I would say building a local first web app is likely
需要在这个过程中的某个时刻发明一些东西。
to require inventing something at some point along the way.
这不像只是将东西推送到 Netlify 并关注
Like this is not like just pushing stuff to Netlify and following
堆栈溢出之外的帖子。
posts off stack overflow.
这是一个新事物，你必须弄清楚一些事情，
This is a new thing and you're going to have to figure some things out
我希望有一天这就像从木头上掉下来一样容易，对吗？
and I hope someday that this is as easy as falling off a log, right?
就像在 Heroku 一样，我们过去总是说让正确的事情变得简单，
Like at Heroku, we used to always say make the right thing the easy thing and
让简单的事情变得正确。
make the easy thing the right thing.
因此，如果我们能做到这一点，如果我们能作为一个社区聚集在一起，那么，你
And so if we can do that, if we can get there together as a community, then, you
知道，希望几年后当人们发现这个播客时，他们会
know, Hopefully when people find this podcast a few years from now, they're
说，哇，我们已经走了很长一段路。
like, wow, we've come a long way.
但今天我想，你知道，我会推荐的是，
But today I think, you know, what I would recommend is like,
你可以构建一个反应应用程序。
you can build a react app.
您可以使用 CRDT，例如 Yjs 或自动合并可能是
You can use a CRDT like, Yjs or auto merge are probably the most
目前最主流的选择。
mainstream choices right now.
但有一些技术我可以
But there are some technologies that I can
哦是的。 还有
Oh yeah.
一个伏尔甘。
And there's a Vulkan.
io。
io.
有 ElectricSQL。
There's ElectricSQL.
有很多人出来尝试新事物。
There's like a ton of people coming out and trying things.
根据您认为合适的方式，您应该尝试一下，看看您能走多远。
And depending on what looks good to you you should try one and see how far you
因此，基本上已经有一个适用于这些用例的工具生态系统了。
So there's basically an ecosystem of tooling already for those use cases.
总有一点相似，这取决于。
there's always a bit of like, it depends.
因此，其中一个可能比另一个更适合您的用例。
So one might better for your use case than another.
但想想这句话怎么说的，我可能需要一路发明一些东西。
But think what saying is like, I need to invent maybe something along the way.
也许我需要做端到端的加密，或者也许我需要
Maybe I need to do end to end encryption, or maybe I need to do
以某种方式做权限控制。 目前还
permission control in a certain way.
没有可用的工具能够完全满足我的需要。
Where none of the available tools yet do exactly what I need.
这就是我需要亲自动手的地方，
And this is where I need to get my own hands dirty,
是的，您可能需要弄清楚如何处理
Yeah, you'll probably need to figure out how to deal with
其中一些离线用例。
some of those offline use cases.
您必须决定要将这些数据提供给谁。
You're going to have to decide who you want to give this data to.
我认为当
I think that's one that everybody kind of wants different
我们与人交谈时，每个人都想要不同的东西。
things when we talk to people.
我认为最终会出现一些标准。
And I think eventually some standards will emerge.
可能会有两到三种模式。
There'll be probably two or three patterns.
大多数人都会采用，但目前，因为每个人的要求
Most people adopt, but at the moment, because everybody's asking
不同，所以人们都在制作不同的东西。
for different things, people are all making different things.
但我认为 ACL 和访问权限是您
But I think that's a that sort of ACLs and access permissions is an area you should
应该花一些时间考虑的一个领域。
expect to spend some time thinking about.
但我得说，仅仅建立一个应用程序就感觉很棒。
But like, I gotta say, it feels amazing to just stand up an app.
在短时间内指向某种同步服务器，然后，
In a short matter of time pointed at some kind of a sync server and then just be,
你知道，与其他人一起工作。
you know, working on it with other people.
我希望每个人都花时间至少拥有
And I hope everybody will take a take the time to at least have that
尝试构建一些小东西的经验，无论是使用 automerge、Y.J.S.
experience to try building something small, whether it's with automerge or Y.
-
J.
S.
、ElectricSQL 还是其他任何东西。
or ElectricSQL or anything else.
那种经历，就是这样。
And that experience, it's just.
这让我大开眼界，因为我花了这么多年时间为云构建这些大型
It's so eye opening for me as somebody who spent all these years building these big
复杂的网络应用程序，实际上，它可以非常简单。
complicated web apps for the cloud to just say actually, it can be pretty simple.
当它很简单时，感觉很棒。
And when it is simple, it feels great.
你感觉自己好像拥有了翅膀。
You feel like you have like, like wings.
你能够行动得如此之快，你就能完成如此之多的事情。
You're just able to move so fast, you're able to get so much done.
这就像有人把铅笔上的砖头取下来一样。
And it's like someone's taking the brick off the pencil.
你只是，就像，你甚至没有意识到你每天忍受了多少麻烦，
You just, like, you don't even realize how much hassle you're putting up
直到它消失。
with every day until it goes away.
所以也许在有人听完这个之后，也许在你的下一个周末，
So maybe after someone's listening to this, maybe on your next weekend,
尝试一下，比如构建一个你想要它一直构建的应用程序，也许是
give it a little try, like build a app you want it to build all along, maybe
React 应用程序，比如加入自动合并，加入 Yjs，看看你能走多远。 会得到的。
React app, like throw in automerge, throw in Yjs, see how far you'll get.
我认为真正的承诺是用户，您的最终用户
And I think the promise is really that users, your end users
将获得更好的软件。
will get much better software.
对于应用程序开发人员来说，您的生活变得更加简单。
And for you as an app developer, your life becomes a lot simpler.
您可以取下那块大砖，然后享受
You can take off that, that big brick and just enjoy drawing
用铅笔绘画和书写的乐趣。
and writing with your pencil.
那，听起来超级令人兴奋。
That, that sounds super exciting.
就像过去两年来看到生态系统的发展一样，我认为我们
And like having seen the ecosystem now for the last two years evolve, I think we
已经走了相当长的路。
have already come quite, quite a long way.
现在有了一个真正的生态系统，你不需要自己重新发明
Now there is a real ecosystem and you don't need to reinvent
一切。
everything by yourself.
如果有人想寻找一些参考资料或灵感，你能
If someone's like looking for some references or some inspiration, can you
指出任何一种已经是本地优先的软件吗？或者我想
point to like any sort of software that is already local first, or I guess like
本地优先是一个范围。
local first is a bit of a spectrum.
有些应用程序可能比其他应用程序更本地化，但是是否有像
Some apps might be more local first than others, but is there like some
人们今天已经使用的某些软件一样，它是定向本地化优先的，
software that people already use today that, that is directionally local first
您可以定位自己？
that you can orient yourself around?
只需查看手机上的核心应用程序集就像一个很好的起点。
Just looking at the core set of apps on your phone is like a nice starting point.
对于网络应用程序来说，有些东西可以追溯到以太垫。
For web apps, there's things going back all the way to like ether pad.
正确的。
Right.
进行离线协作的地方。
Where you have offline collaboration.
然后，如果您想尝试构建自己的体验，请使用
And then if you want to try and build your own experience
automerge.org/docs/quickstart。
automerge.org/docs/quickstart.
你知道，你可以站起来，体验
You know, you can get up and, you know, experience that feeling of building
为自己构建本地优先软件的感觉。
local-first software for yourself.
我认为从用户的角度来看，我们认为大多数应用程序运行速度很快，或者
I think most apps that we from a user perspective, see as working fast or
您也相信在乘坐飞机或火车时可以使用它们。
that you also trust to use them while you're traveling on a plane, on a train.
我认为它们都可能是，尽管它们
I think they are all probably, even though they don't have a local first
在软件盒子上还没有本地第一标签，但它们可能已经更加本地第一了。
label yet on the software box, they are probably already more local first.
是的，我认为，无论谁试图构建
And yeah, this is, I think, whoever's trying to build something
下一个东西，如果你能够亲自体验这一点，我认为这是
next if you get to experience that for yourself, I think that's the
说服自己的最简单的方法。
easiest way to convince yourself.
我正在考虑一些我认为我每天都会使用的软件，
I'm thinking of some software that I think that I use on a daily basis,
无论是线性的还是
whether like, whether it's like, something like, Linear or something
超人之类的应用程序，虽然我不确定它们是否
like superhuman, those sort of apps, while I'm not sure whether they were
来自 一开始，意味着本地优先，我认为他们已经以
from the inception, meant to be local first, I think they've directionally
越来越本地优先的方式定向发展，可能仍然像
evolved in a way that is more and more local first, there's probably still like
服务器一样大量参与，但就客户端而言，它变得更加聪明。
servers heavily involved, but in terms of that client is getting a lot smarter.
我认为这已经是朝这个方向迈出的重要一步。
I think that's already an important step in that direction.
这当然就是这些应用程序感觉很棒的原因。
And that's certainly why those apps feel great.
阿门。
Amen.
因此，也许在结束之前，您现在最关心的“本地优先”中的哪些主题是您
So maybe before wrapping up, what are some topics within Local First that are
花费大量时间思考的，
very top of mind for you right now that you spend a lot of time thinking about
以及您希望我们在一两年内取得更大进展的 时间？
and where you hope that we'll be a lot further along in one or two years time?
哦。
Ooh.
我认为对我来说，目前最大的设计问题是
I think for me, the biggest design questions right now are around
版本控制和版本控制。
versioning and version control.
在研究本地优先软件并与
One of the things we've found as we've studied local-first software and talked
作家和创作者交谈时，我们发现的一件事是，嗯，这种云的想法就像是，
to writers and creators is that, um, this idea of the cloud as like, Sort
任何人都可以观看你工作的圆形监狱，就像非常深刻的一样 让
of the panopticon where anyone can watch you work is like really deeply
很多人感到不舒服，因此探索这些创造性隐私的想法
uncomfortable to a lot of people and so exploring these ideas of creative
以及以软件开发人员的工作方式工作的能力，即在
privacy and the ability to work the way software developers work, which is you
准备好共享之前私下工作。
work private until you're ready to share.
我真的很渴望探索这些想法并带来这些想法。
I'm really eager to explore those ideas and bring those.
对于世界其他地方，您的Google 文档，您应该能够
To the rest of the world, your Google Docs, you should be able
以相同的离线方式工作。
to work in that same offline way.
所以我认为整个......
So I think that whole...
关于以新的方式将版本控制结合在一起的问题是一个很大的问题。
Question about like bringing together version control in new ways is a big one.
身份验证、授权、访问控制、共享
Authentication, authorization, access control, sharing
权限等等。
permissions, that kind of stuff.
我认为这实际上是非常密切相关的。
I think it's actually quite closely related.
我认为我们将在这个领域看到很多进展。
I think that's an area we're going to see a lot of progress around.
我认为应用程序模型将继续发展，对吗？
I think the app models are going to continue to evolve, right?
喜欢。
Like.
自动合并是基于文档的，电动 SQL是基于数据库的，而 Riffle 是基于 SQLite 的。
Auto merge is document based, electric SQL is database based and Riffle is SQLite.
其实两者都是对的。
Both are actually right.
我不认为这是一个或另一个，但我认为探索这种关系将
I don't think it's one or the other, but I think exploring kind of that relationship
是一个很大的领域。
there is going to be a big area.
我认为有很多关于安全和加密的内容，
I think there's a lot of stuff around security and encryption,
端到端加密将会随之展开。
end to end encryption that's going to unfold and with it.
那句话是什么？
What's that what's that quote?
我认为是Leah Kistner，也就是说，密码学是一种将
I think it was Leah Kistner, which is , cryptography is a
许多问题转化为密钥管理问题的技术。
technique for turning many problems into key management problems.
所以我认为在接下来的几年里我们会看到很多这样的情况。
so I think we're going to see a lot of that over the next few years.
我认为这只是表面现象。
I think that's just scraping the surface.
我认为所有这一切也将与类似的
And I think all of this though will also intersect with like
应用程序开发模型相交叉。
application development models.
只是考虑其他类型的交叉事物，
Just thinking about other kind of intersecting things, another big part of
我们仍然相对不成熟的另一个重要部分是决定同步什么以及何时同步它，
where we're still relatively immature is deciding what to sync and when to sync it,
我们在 Ink 和 Switch 中有这样的座右铭，这就像
There's this motto we have at Ink and Switch, which is like, results on
下一帧的结果 你的钱回来了吗？
the next frame are your money back.
我们希望你所做的一切都以一百赫兹的速度运行，所有这些都不像服务器的
We want everything you do to run at a hundred hertz, none of this like a
一百毫秒循环时间，然后你就可以开始绘画了。
hundred millisecond round time to the server, and then you get to paint.
不，就像当您与系统交互时一样，您应该在
No, like when you interact with the system, you should see the response
下次屏幕刷新时看到响应。
the next time your screen refreshes.
这意味着在 100 赫兹的屏幕上，您有 10 毫秒的时间来完成所有操作。
So that means on a hundred hertz screen, you got 10 milliseconds to do everything.
所以如果服务器距离 50 毫秒就太晚了，
And so if the server is 50 milliseconds away is too late,
你不能询问服务器，对吗？
you can't ask the server, right?
如果你想通过下一个数据获得东西，这意味着你
If you want to have things by the next data, that means you
需要在用户询问之前就已经获取数据，
need to out there already get the data before the user even asks
这对你的数据架构的性能有很大影响，
That has big implications on your data architecture on like performance,
所以很多是的。
So many Yeah.
事情需要记在记忆里。
Things need to be in memory.
您如何管理内存使用？
How do you manage memory use?
低带宽连接怎么样？
What about like low bandwidth connections?
所以，是的，我认为同步优化和后台
So yeah, I think that whole area of like sync optimization and background
同步等整个领域非常重要。
sync and so on is really important.
这是一个已经考虑过的领域，但我们还没有看到
And it's an area that have thought about, but we haven't seen a ton of
在实施方面取得大量进展，因为直到你真正拥有足够的用户
progress on implementations yet, because until you actually have enough users
和足够的使用量来真正推动这一点之前，
and enough usage to really drive that,
在未来的剧集中也会更深入地探讨非常有趣的主题 。
Really interesting topics to dive deeper on in future episodes as well.
有一个主题对我来说也很突出，我认为我们还没有实现这一点，
There is one topic that also stands out to me that I think we're not there
那就是跨应用程序协作或跨应用程序互操作性。
yet which is cross app collaboration or cross app interoperability.
就像我们一样。 朝着
So as we're.
我们的生活中拥有越来越多人工智能的方向发展
Steering in the direction where we have like more and more AI in our
，到目前为止，所有这些人工智能都在像
lives and all of those AIs so far are looking also that they run on like
某个地方的远程服务器等上运行。
somewhere's remote server, et cetera.
现在我们将把越来越多的数据输入到那些我
And now we're going to feed more and more of our data into those I
希望看到的世界中，人工智能也可以类似。
would love to see a world where like the AIs can also similar, like the.
就像我们正在构建的程序也在我们的设备上运行一样。
Like the programs that we're building also run on our devices.
现在我们需要向这些人提供我们的数据。
Now we need to make our data available to those.
让这些程序和人工智能相互协作。
Have those programs and those AIs collaborate between each other.
所以以同样的方式，就像我脑子里的所有东西一样。
So in the same ways, like all the stuff I have in my own head.
从与你的对话，从与他人的对话，我的想法
From conversations with you, from conversations with others, my mind is
就像能够，我所进行的所有这些不同的交互几乎就像
like able to, all of those different interactions I have are almost like
小应用程序一样，它们自然可以协作，但
little apps and they naturally can collaborate yet my contacts app that runs
我的计算机上运行的联系人应用程序和我的电子邮件应用程序，除非它们 来自 Apple 并且确实集成了它，
on my machine and my email app, unless they're from Apple and does integrate it,
否则他们不会喜欢，应用程序之间的集成故事等等？
otherwise they can't like, what does that integration story between apps, et cetera?
那看起来像什么？
What does that look like?
我认为这是其基础。
And I think the foundation for that is.
数据需要位于设备上。
The data needs to be on the device.
现在我们需要在上面构建一些东西，以使其更容易互操作。
And now we need to build something on top that makes it easier to interoperate.
该数据在应用程序之间共享。
That data is shared across apps.
这也是我非常兴奋的一个话题。
That's a whole topic that I'm also really excited about.
因此，我们在 Income Switch 中将这种软件称为可塑性软件，这对我们来说是一个非常
So we call that malleable software at Income Switch, and it's a very
活跃的研究领域。
active area of research for us.
我们刚刚发表了一篇名为《EmbarkToday》的论文，截至本次录音有关
We've just published a paper called Embark Today as of this recording about that
https://inkandswitch.com/embark，我们在其中准确讨论了其中一些问题。
https://inkandswitch.com/embark where we talk exactly about some of these problems.
关于自动合并设计，我
One really cool thing about auto merges design that I haven't seen
在其他系统中没有见过的一件非常酷的事情是，系统的粒度意味着任何
in other systems is that the grain of the system means that any apps
共享备份同步服务器的应用程序。
which share a backup sync server.
只要知道如何解释数据，就可以加载彼此的数据。
can load each other's data as long as they know how to interpret it.
而且，你知道，这有点像共享 SQL 数据库，但没有
And, you know, it's a little bit like sharing a SQL database, but without
共享 SQL 数据库的所有问题，因为数据库
all the problems of sharing a SQL database, because the database is not
不像共享资源，你必须担心人们敲打，对吗？
like the shared resource that you have to worry about people hammering, right?
您可以将数据放入同步服务器中，然后任何东西都可以查询它。
you can just put data in a sync server and then anything can query it out.
所以，我不得不说，这太棒了。
And so, I got to say, it's awesome.
我用它所有的时间。
I use it all the time.
当我损坏某些东西时，我可以在另一个应用程序中打开它并修复它。
When I break something, I can open it up in another app and fix it.
你知道，我有一整套小应用程序，它们首先是本地的，
You know, I have a whole suite of little apps that are local first
现在可以对我们的数据进行协作。
that collaborate on our data now.
是的，好吧，当我们有话要说时，我们会在将来的某个时候对此进行更多讨论
And yeah, well, we'll say more about that sometime in the future
。
when we have something to say.
彼得，非常感谢您与我们分享有关本地优先的所有内容。
Peter, thank you so much for sharing all of that about Local First with us.
我认为这是一个非常非常漫长的旅程的开始，我想
I think this is the beginning of a much, much longer journey where I want
听到更多不同的声音，比如人们使用本地优先构建应用程序
to hear a lot more different voices, like people building apps with Local
，人们构建工具来帮助其他开发人员构建本地优先应用程序。
First, people building tools to help other developers build Local First apps.
所有我们今天在这里才刚刚触及表面的事情。
All the things we've just barely touched the surface here today.
非常感谢您来到这个节目，我期待
So thank you so much for coming on the show and I'm looking forward
着您很快回来。
to having you back hopefully soon.
是的。
Yeah.
这很有趣。
It was a lot of fun.
Take
Awesome
感谢您收听Local First FM 播客。
Thank you for listening to the Local First FM podcast.
如果您喜欢本集但尚未订阅，请订阅并
If you've enjoyed this episode and haven't done so already, please subscribe and
在您收听的任何地方留下评论。
leave a review wherever you're listening.
如果您认为您的朋友
Please also consider telling your friends about it, if you think they
可能对本地优先感兴趣，也请考虑将其告知他们。
could be interested in Local First.
再次感谢 Expo 和蟹状星云对本播客的支持。
Thank you again to Expo and Crab Nebula for supporting this podcast.